In this example, we will improve our
hand written digit recognizer which will
implement it in week two.
If we use the [INAUDIBLE] for this.
Remember, in week two,
if you used soft [INAUDIBLE] flow and
got an accuracy of around 92%.
So let's see if we can do better.
We will start with a couple of imports.
Again, most of the frameworks
are providing the most
interesting data sets as imports.
So in this case, we will used the end
of this data set provided by We will
use the all ready known sequential model
type and we import through layer types.
Then you all ready know where it is.
So, drop out which is a functionality
to prevent over fitting is usually only
a parameter to a layer but it carries,
it is moderate as a separate layer.
Since deep learning is in anyway
nothing else than taking functions.
This perfectly make sense.
So that during every iteration,
a number of random neurons gets
freezed and deviates an updated.
So this prevents over-fitting, and
that model generalizes better.
Is a layer which reduces
the dimensionality
of a which we will see later.
Then you put a tool in important layers
for convolution in your networks.
Is the two dimensional convolutions
layer which perfectly fits image data.
And next, pulling 2D as
the name suggests is a pulling
layer using the max pulling
function again in 2D.
The we can specify later.
Allows us to access properties
of the underlying backend with
a special function in this case, we could
access those functions using capital k.
We defined some constants,
you should all ready know what those mean,
then we need to find the shape of
the images which are 28 by 28 pixels.
Note that in this example we are not
using a vector of 784 pixels,
but the 3D tensor of 28 by 28 by 1.
The third dimension usually is
reserved for the color venue, and
has a shape of three.
Let's load the data.
This is a very convenient method,
because it will try to [INAUDIBLE]
off four non paid arrays.
The FE input vector to neural
network with the size of 784, and
the effort target vector in the dimension
one which contains only the class labels.
From zero to nine, and it all through
the times to split between training and
test data.
Now it's time to access the properties
of the tensor flow back end by using
the key variable.
Since I auto supported we
have to define the way,
how the color information
is encoded in the image.
Some case of the it would
expect a 28 by 28 by 1.
But here we needed 1 by 28 by 28.
If only one here, because its
a mono-form image and not the image.
You apply some data pre-processing by
casting the data and normalizing it.
Analyzing the straight forward here,
but just to write by 55 and
we obtain a very range between zero and
one.
It was on in order to verify
if the shape is correct, and
also to count the number of training and
text examples.
So since the label is recorded
as a singular mention
with variables between zero and nine,
we transform this to one hot and
call it vector,
using the caret two category invention.
We started a sequential model and
added a 2D convolutional layer.
This layer has 32 neurons, and
uses a three by three matrix
to scan our body image.
We're using activation function, and we
define the input shape as 28 by 28 by 1,
because you're using the This is
followed by narrow 2D convolution layer.
This time, we are specifying 64 neurons.
Followed by this,
we are adding a 2D max pooling layer,
which is counting the image
by a 2 by 2 matrix.
Now we drop our 25% of
the neurons in each iteration.
Now we've down the 28 by 28 by 1
into a vector of 784 elements.
And then, we add a fully
connected layer with 128 neurons.
Again, we drop out, this time 50%
of the neurons in each iteration.
Finally, we end up with a fully connected
layer, with ten output nuerons.
Note that we change the activation
function from value to soft next,
which is an ideal fit for
our ten element one hot encoded vector.
As cost function,
we defined categorical across entropy
which is a very good fit for
my declassification task.
It's great to send out data,
we use other data which turns out
to converge best given the dataset,
and that you're in a topology.
Then we start training
with the usual parameters.
After training, we checked
the accuracy using the test data set.
Finally, you print loss in the accuracy
on a test data set, and we are done.
Let's run this.
After training the 60,000 examples,
we noticed that we are doing
quite well on the training data.
And if you look at the test data,
you see that we are doing an amazing job.
We went up from 92% accuracy
with softmax equation,
to 99% accuracy using this very
simple convolutional neural network.
In the next video, you will see how more
complex convolutional neural network
can give us amazing recites,
and image classification.