in the last video we distract what is
the deep l-larry neural network and also
talked about the notation we use to
describe such networks in this video you
see how you can perform for propagation
in a deep network as usual let's first
go over what forward propagation will
look like for a single training example
X and then later on we'll talk about the
vectorized version where you want to
carry out forward propagation on the
entire training set at the same time but
some given a single training example X
here's how you compute the activations
of the first layer so for this first
layer you compute z1 equals W 1 times X
plus b1 so W 1 and B 1 of parameters
that affect the activations in layer 1
right where this is there one of the
neural network and then you compute the
activations for that layer to be equal
to G of Z 1 and the destination function
G depends on what layer you're at and
maybe index AB has the activation
function from there 1 so if you do that
you've now computed the activations from
layer 1
how about layer to say that layer well
you would then compute Z 2 equals W 2 A
1 plus B 2 and then so the activation of
layer 2 is the way matrix times the
output of layer 1 so is that value plus
the bias vector for layer 2 and then a2
equals the activation function apply to
z2 ok so that's it for layer 2 and so on
and so forth until you get to the output
layer that's layer 4 where you would
have that Z 4 is equal to the parameters
for that layer times the activations
from the previous layer
Plus that by this vector and then
similarly a four equals G of v4 and so
that's how you compute your estimated
output Y hat so just one thing to notice
X here is also equal to a zero because
the input feature vector X is also the
activations of layer 0 so we scratch out
X and with a cross for X and put a 0
here then you know all of these
equations they see look the same right
the general rule is that VL is equal to
WL times a of L minus 1 plus B L 1 there
and then the activations so that layer
is the activation function applied to
the values Z so that's the general for
propagation equation so we've done all
this for a single training example how
about for doing it in a vectorized way
for the whole training set at the same
time the equations look quite similar as
before for the first layer you would
have Capital Z 1 equals W 1 times
capital X plus B 1 and then a 1 equals G
of Z 1 right and bearing in mind that X
is equal to a 0 these are just you know
the training examples stacked in
different columns you could take this
let me scratch out X so you can put a 0
there and then so the next layer looks
similar
Z 2 equals W 2 A 1 plus B 2 and a 2
equals G of Z 2
we're just taking these vectors e or a
and so on and stacking them up so this
is V vector for the first training
example V vector for the second training
example and so on down to the M train
example and stacking these in columns
and calling this Capital Z all right and
similarly for capital A just as capital
X all the training examples are column
vectors smacks left to right and then
again end of this process you end up
with Y hat which is equal to G of v4 so
this is also equal to a 4 and that's the
predictions on all the view training
examples is stacked horizontally so just
to summarize our notation I'm going to
modify this up here our notation allows
us to replace lowercase Z and a with the
uppercase counterparts is that already
looks like a capital D and that gives
you the vectorized version the fourth
obligation that you carry out on the
entire training set at a time where a 0
is X now if you look at this
implementation of vectorization it looks
like that there is going to be a for
loop here right so it's left for l
equals 1 to 4 for l equals 1 through
capital L then you have to compute the
activations for layer 1 then for layer 2
then to layer 3 and then 4 therefore so
seems that there is a for loop here and
I know that when implementing your
networks we usually want to get rid of
explicit for loops but this is one place
where I don't think there's any way to
implement this over other than explicit
for loop so we're in implementing for
propagation it is perfectly OK to have a
for loop they compute the activations
for layer 1 then there are 2 then they
are threes and therefore no one knows
and I don't think there is this any way
to do this without a for loops that goes
from 1 to capital L from 1 through the
total number of layers and in your
network so this place is perfectly okay
to have an explicit form so
that's it for the notation for deep
neural networks as well as how to do for
propagation in these networks if the
pieces we've seen so far looks a little
bit familiar to you that's because what
we've seen is taking a piece very
similar to what you've seen in the
neural network with a single hidden
layer and just repeating that more times
now turns out that we implemented deep
neural network one of the ways to
increase your odds of having above free
implementation is to think very
systematic and carefully about the
matrix dimensions you're working with so
when I'm trying to develop my own code I
often pull a piece of paper and just
think carefully through so the
dimensions of the matrix I'm working
with let's see how you could do that in
the next video