in the earlier videos from this week as
well as from the videos from the past
several weeks you've already seen the
basic building blocks of board
propagation and back propagation the key
components you need to implement a deep
neural network let's see how you can put
these components together to build a
deep net use the network with a few
layers let's pick one layer and look at
the computations focusing on just that
layer for now so for layer L you have
some parameters WL and Bo and for the
forward prop you will input the
activations a L minus one from the
previous layer and output Al so the way
we did this previously was you compute Z
l equals WL x al minus one plus BL um
and then al equals G of Z L right so
that's how you go from the input al
minus one to the output Al and it turns
out that for later use will be useful to
also cache the value ZL so let me
include this on cache as well because
storing the value Z L will be useful for
backward for the back propagation step
later and then for the backward step or
three for the back propagation step
again focusing on computation for this
layer L you're going to implement a
function that inputs da of L and outputs
da L minus one and just a special the
details the input is actually da FL as
well as the cache so you have available
to you the value of ZL that you compute
it and
in addition to outputting GL minus 1 you
will output
you know the gradients you want in order
to implement gradient descent for
learning ok so this is the basic
structure of how you implement this
forward step I'm going to call it a
forward function as well as backward
step we shall call it back wave function
so just to summarize in layer L you're
going to have you know the forward step
or the forward property' forward
function input a L minus 1 and output al
and in order to make this computation
you need to use WL n PL um and also
output a cache which contains ZL and
then on the backward function using the
back prop step will be another function
then now inputs the AFL and outputs da
ll minus 1 so it tells you given the
derivatives respect to these activations
that's da FL what are the derivatives or
how much do I wish you know a L minus 1
changes computed derivatives respect to
D activations from the previous layer
within this box right you need to use WL
and BL and it turns out along the way
you end up computing DZ l um and then
this box this backward function can also
output DW l and DB l well now sometimes
using red arrows to denote the backward
generations so if you prefer we could
draw these arrows in red so if you can
implement these two functions then the
basic computation of the mirror network
will be as follows you're going to take
the input features a 0 see that in and
that will compute the activations of the
first layer let's call that a 1 and to
do that you needed W 1 and B 1 and then
we'll also you know cache
the way z1 now having done that you feed
that this is the second layer and then
using W 2 and B 2 you're going to
compute the activations our next layer a
2 and so on until eventually you end up
outputting a capital L which is equal to
Y hat and along the way we cashed all of
these on values Z so that's the forward
propagation step now for the back
propagation step what we're going to do
will be a backward sequence of
iterations in which you're going
backwards and computing gradients like
so so as you're going to feed in here da
L and then this box will give us da of L
minus 1 and so on until we get da - da 1
you could actually get one more output
to compute da 0 but this is derivative
respect your input features which is not
useful at least for training the weights
of these are supervised neural networks
so you could just stop it there belong
the way back prop also ends up
outputting DW l DB l right this used
upon so wo and BL um this would output d
w3 g p3 and so on so you enter
computing all the derivatives you need
until just a maybe so in the structure
of this a little bit more right these
boxes will use those parameters of slow
WL PL and it turns out that we'll see
later that inside these boxes we'll end
up computing disease as well so one
innovation of training for a new network
involves starting with a zero which is X
and going through for profit as follows
computing Y hat and then using that to
compute this and then back prop right
doing that and now you have all these
derivative terms and so you know W will
get updated as some W minus the learning
rate times DW right for each of the
layers and similarly for B right now
we've compute the back prop and have all
these derivatives so that's one
iteration of gradient descent for your
neural network now before moving on just
one more implementational detail
conceptually will be useful to think of
the cashier as storing the value of Z
for the backward functions but when you
implement this you see this in the
programming exercise when you implement
it
you find that the cash may be a
convenient way to get the value of the
parameters at W 1 V 1 into the backward
function as well so the program exercise
you actually spawn the cash is Z as well
as W and B all right so to store z2w to
be to go from an implementational
standpoint I just find this a convenient
way to just you know get the parameters
copied to where you need to need to use
them later when you're computing back
propagation so that's just an
implementational detail that you see
when you do the programming exercise so
you've now seen one of the basic
building blocks for implementing a deep
neural network image layer there's a for
propagation step and there's a
corresponding backward propagation step
and as
cash deposit information from one to the
other in the next video we'll talk about
how you can actually implement these
building blocks let's go into the next
video