So, let's start with some Course Logistics.
So this is a four-weeks course.
In the first week,
we started linear algebra and neural network theory.
In the second week,
we introduced you to some neural network frameworks like TensorFlow,
Keras, PyTorch, Deeplearning4j, system of it.
And in the third week,
we will show you some practical examples of
deep learning in real-life industry use cases, for example,
an image classification, natural-language processing,
anomaly detection of sensor data,
or times use forecasting of stock market data.
In the fourth week,
it's all about deployment.
So in week four, we'll show you how you can scale and deploy
your neural network on clusters of CPU and GPU machines and make it ready for production.
Each week has one created programming assignment and a couple of quizzes.
After you have completed all of requirement assignments and the quizzes,
you will get a certification and the benchmark course.
That is a specialization that means if you complete this course and some others,
you we get the certification that you are IBM Watson IoT Certified Data Scientist.
So I think this is pretty cool.
I hope that you are enjoying the course, and let's have