Welcome to the lecture on Linear Algebra.
So before we start,
let's have a look at some important terms.
Let's start with Scalar.
Scalar is basically any number,
like 1, 5, 23, or 42.
But we are not limited to integers.
Also, real numbers are scalars,
like 23.5, for example.
If you group a number of scalars together,
you end up with a vector.
This is a vector of length four.
And this is one of length three.
And this is one of length five.
So vector can easily be
confused with tuple.
So this guy here can be either a vector or
a tuple.
But this is a tuple.
Can you see the difference?
So in a vector, each element has to have
the same type, whereas in the tuple,
types can be mixed.
A Matrix is the big brother of a vector.
It's basically a list
of equal-sized vectors.
Notice that the number of rows and
columns can be different, but
each element has to have the same type.
A Matrix has n columns and m rows,
therefore we call these
matrices m- by- n matrices.
So the left one is a 3- by- 4 matrix
whereas the right one is a 2- by- 5
matrix.
Finally, the coolest guy
is called the Tensor.
Here, you can see a 3D tensor which is
basically nothing else like a matrix,
but in three dimensions.
Tensors can be quite handy in
image processing, for example.
So you can have one dimension for
the height, one for the width, and
one for colors, alpha channel, and
focus information, for example.
So a tensor is more general term for
special cases.
So, for example,
a zero-dimensional tensor is a scalar,
a one-dimensional tensor is a vector,
a two-dimensional tensor is a matrix.
So now, you can really show off
in front of your colleagues
by knowing all those terms.
So, let's start with some math.
The most important mathematical
operation on tensors
used in this course is multiplication.
We can multiple two scalars, so
let's start with two integers, 2 and 3.
If you multiply them together we get 6.
But we can also multiply two vectors.
Note that the column-wise notation
is the most common in math.
This multiplication is
called the dot product or
scalar product because
it returns a scalar.
We won't cover the cross product or
the vector product here.
So that dot product simply takes
the first element of the first vector and
multiplies it with the first
element of the second vector.
Then it does the same for
the second elements of the vectors.
And finally the rest.
So now, all those immediate
products are summed up.
And the reciting sum is
the solution to the dot product.
Generally speaking,
a vector multiplication is
a linear combination of those.
This is very handy in deep learning,
because one vector normally is used for
the data, and one vector is used for
the training weights,
which you will see later.
Using this notation, we can also make use
of GPUs or SIMD instruction sets on CPUs.
Note that both vectors need
to be of the same size.
We will use NumPy as central library for
linear algebra in Python.
So let's import it.
Now, we create two vectors, A and B.
Note, that those are implemented as
one-dimensional NumPy arrays in Python.
Now we'll use the dot method of
the NumPy area object in order to do
the calculation.
Not only a multiplication between
two vectors is defined, also,
multiplication between a matrix and
a vector.
So just take the first element of the
first row and column of the matrix, and
multiply it with the first
element of the vector.
[BLANK AUDIO] And then put it as the first
element of the restarting vector.
Then repeat the steps for
the second column's first element, and
the second element of the vector.
Finally, repeat the steps for
the third column,
first row of the matrix with
the third element of the vector.
And then, we repeat the same steps for
the second row of the matrix.
And then we sum up all those components.
End result is a two element vector.
So this is nothing else than two vector
dot products calculated in one go.
But the first vector is encoded in
the first row of the matrix and
the second vector in the second row.
This is also very handy for SIMD or
GPU instruction sets where we can speed
up those calculations dramatically.
Also, the notation becomes more concise.
As long as the number of columns matches
the number of elements in the vector,
we can apply this calculation for
arbitrary factors.
Vector matrix multiplication
is just a special
case of matrix-matrix multiplication,
but we do not need to cover this here.
Let's implement a vector matrix
multiplication in NumPy.
We will start with the same vector,
a and b,
and turn it into a matrix using
a two dimensional NumPy array.
Now we can use the same
overloaded dot method
in order to calculate the matrix
vector multiplication.
Note that result is the same as two
sequential vector-vector dot products.
But now, this function is expressed
in a single call which can be
easily parallelized in an SIMD or
GPU instruction set.
So this was enough math for now.
You should be able to understand
most of the math in your networks.
So let's get started with
our first neural network.