LSTMs are so powerful that we can dedicate
a whole lecture on how they are working.
You could take an entire course on LSTMs,
and
if you are planning to do so please
check out the description of this video.
But we will try to give you a more
intuitive way of looking at LSTMs.
So this is a single neuron in LSTMs.
By the way, LSTMs stands for
Long Short Term Memory Networks.
And s in the feet forward network,
it marks an input xt,
to an output vector, ht, by using
weights and an activation function.
Note that the same holds whether
you are using scalars or
vectors as input and output.
But we now see a lot of
additional components.
So the first thing we notice is that there
is no direct connection between xt and ht.
All data flows through ct,
which is the so called cell state.
Cell state is the actual
memory of the LSTM neuron.
Notice that there are three additional
units present in a LSTM neuron,
an input gate, an output gate,
and a forget gate.
Those three gates
are controlling the state of ct.
The way how this is
controlled is as follows.
So have a look at the input first.
The first thing we notice is that xt is
not only used as input of the neuron but
also as input to the gate.
So the input gate, as the other gates,
has a separate weight vector which
is straight from the input data and
learns to control the influx of
information into the cell's data city.
This is done by a vector dot product
between the input xt after it has been
squashed by the activation function and
the output of the input gate.
In other words,
through the weight vector of the input
gate the neuron can learn
from creating data.
When it is a good idea to open the gate
and have the input start in the cell.
Often it is a bad idea
to remember things and
close the influx information
into the cell state ct.
Note that this is a continuous value, so
just like a wall which can be
partially opened and closed.
Finally it is important to notice that
all the cell state has an influence on
the gate.
This is again accomplished through
a separate weight vector so
that the actual input gate is controlled
by the historic cell state as well
as by the actual value of xt.
So now let's have a look
at the output gate.
Again, it is controlled by the actual
value xt and by the actual cell state ct.
Here the output gate controls how
much of cell state ct gets output
to down stimulants connected to ht.
So this topology is the initial LSTM
proposed by and Hoover in 1997.
In 1999 Felix and
added an additional component,
the forget gate.
They discovered that without the
capability of forgetting the cell state ct
may grow indefinitely and eventually
causes the network to break down.
Again the forget gate is controlled
by the actual input xt and
the current cell state ct.
And again through calculation of induct
product between the output of the forget
gate and the previous cell state ct,
it controls how much of the actual
cell state ct is preserved.
Another exotic but totally exciting
neronetwork technology is an autoencoder.
So let's learn about it
in the next lecture.