So this video covers activation
functions and from the previous lecture,
you have maybe remember that we have
the sigmoid activation function
used in logistic regression.
So this is the so-called logistic sigmoid
function and this is applied twice.
So activation function,
it's non-linear due to the model and
with only one single hidden layer, having
or learning the activation function,
a neural network is the universal
function approximator,
capable of learning any
mathematical function.
In contrast, if you only have
linear layers, then you can add as
many hidden layers as you like, you never
get a universal function approximator.
So there's also another activation
function widely used, this is tanh.
So tanh has the advantage, as you can see,
that it also covers the negative range.
So if you have data which in the negative
range, tanh might be better.
And it's also used in the output
layer of binary classification.
In case of multiclass specification,
the output layer uses soft mix.
So soft mix is defined as a function
which takes the value of z,
and then takes e to the power of it.
And then it divides by the sum of e taken
to the power of all the other c values.
So this soft mix function has
the property that R class
probabilities are summed into 1.
In the case of multiclass specification,
the actual class you have predicted
will assemble in a value close to 1.
And all other classes
are assembled in values close to 0.
So this activation function ideally
fits to one hat encoded vector in
the output layer.
So this is another activation
function which is called ReLU.
So ReLU doesn't really look non-linear,
but actually it is,
because a linear function is only a line.
And it turns out that the combination
of multiple ReLU activation functions,
you also can approximate
any mathematical function.
ReLU is the most used
activation function today.
This is, first of all, because
the computation of complexity is less, and
your networks also tend to
converge faster using ReLU.
One problem with ReLU is that
it can cause dead neurons,
because of a range value output is 0,
therefore, there is a valuation of ReLU.
So this is called leaky ReLU, as you can
see on the negative side there is a little
value, and that increases the value range,
and also prevents that neurons.
So in case your neural network
training doesn't work perfectly,
you just can try leaky ReLU or also
there's a variation called random ReLU.
So it's best to start with ReLU for
the input and the hidden layers.
And for the output layer,
it depends on your task.
So if you are relinear regressor,
you use a linear output unit,
and if you are creating a classifier,
you use soft mix or sigmoid.
And nobody, of course,
stops you from trying other things.
So the next video,
it will tell you something about
the bias variance tradeoff.
Or in other words how to prevent
overfitting of a neural network