welcome back in this week's you learn to
implement a neural network before diving
into the technical details I wanted in
this video to give you a quick overview
of what you'll be seeing in this week's
videos so if you don't follow all the
details in this video don't worry about
it we'll delve in the technical details
in the next few videos but for now let's
give a quick overview of how you
implement in your network last week we
had talked about logistic regression and
we saw how this model corresponds to the
following computation graph where you
didn't put the features X and parameters
W MB that allows you to compute Z which
is then used to compute a and we were
using a interchangeably with this output
Y hat and then you can compute the loss
function l a new network looks like this
and as I'd already previously alluded
you can form a neural network by
stacking together a lot of little
sigmoid units whereas previously this
node corresponds to two steps of
calculations the first three compute the
Z value second is it computes this a
value in this dual network this stack of
notes will correspond to a Z like
calculation like this as well as an a
like calculation like that and then that
node will correspond to another Z and
another 8 like calculation so the
notation which we should use later will
look like this
first what inputs the features X
together with some parameters W and B
and this will allow you to compute z1 so
new notation that one should use is that
we'll use a superscript square bracket 1
to refer to quantities associated with
this stack of nodes called a lair and
then later we'll use superscript square
bracket 2 to refer to quantities
associated with Daniel really that's
called another layer of the network and
the superscript square brackets like we
have here are not to be confused with
the superscript round brackets which we
used to refer to individual training
examples so whereas X
supersu round bracket I referred to the
I've trained example superscript square
bracket 1 and 2 refers to these
different um layers layer 1 and layer 2
in this network but they're going on
after computing z1 similar to logistic
regression there will be a computation
to compute a 1 and that's just some
sigmoid of z1 and then you compute Z 2
using another linear equation and then
compute a 2 and a 2 is the final output
of the neural network and will also be
used interchangeably with Y hat so I
know there was a lot of details but the
key intuition to take away is that
whereas for logistic regression we had
this Z followed by a calculation and
this new network here we just do it
multiple times as a CV followed by a
calculation and a Z followed by a
calculation and then you finally compute
the loss at the end and you remember
that for the just regression we had in
some backward calculation in order to
compute derivatives are so confusing
da easy and so on so in the same way in
a new network we'll end up doing a
backward calculation that looks like
this and we jump you end up computing da
2 DZ 2 that allows you to compute so DW
2 DB 2 and so on in this order the right
to less backward calculation that is
denoting with the red arrows so thank
you
quick overview of what a new network
websites based you take a logistic
regression and repeating it twice I know
there was a lot of new notation lot of
new details don't worry about to get and
follow everything we'll go into the
details most slowly in the next few
videos so let's go on to the next video
we'll stop to talk about the neural
network representation