why does your new network need a
nonlinear activation function turns out
that for your new network to compute
interesting functions you do need to
take a nonlinear activation function
less you want so just the for prop
equations for the neural network why
don't we just get rid of this get rid of
the function G and set a1 equals Z 1 or
alternatively you could say that G of Z
is equal to Z right sometimes this is
called the linear activation function
maybe a better name for it would be the
identity activation function because
they're just outputs whatever was input
for the purpose of this
what if a2 was just equal to z2 it turns
out if you do this then this model is
just computing Y or Y hat as a linear
function of your input features x2 take
the first two equations if you have that
a1 is equal to z1 is equal to w1 X plus
B and if then a2 is equal to z2 is equal
to W 2 a1 plus B then if you take the
definition of a1 and plug it in there
you find that a2 is equal to W 2 times W
1 X plus b1 a bit all right so this is
um a 1 plus B 2 and so this simplifies
to W 2 W 1 X plus W 2 b1 plus b2 so this
it's just let's call this w prime b
prime so it is just equal to w prime X
plus B Prime
if you were to use linear activation
functions or we go to call them identity
activation functions then the new
network is just outputting a linear
function of the input and we'll talk
about deep networks later new networks
with many many layers many many hidden
layers and it turns out that if you use
a linear activation function or
alternatively if you don't have an
activation function then no matter how
many layers your neural network has
always doing is just computing a linear
activation function so you might as well
not have any hidden layers some of the
cases that briefly mentioned it turns
out that if you have a linear activation
function here and a sigmoid function
here then this model is no more
expressive than standard logistic
regression without any hidden layer so I
won't bother to prove that but you could
try to do so if you want but the
take-home is that a linear hidden layer
is more or less useless because on the
composition of two linear functions is
itself a linear function so unless you
throw a non-linearity in there then
you're not computing more interesting
functions even as you go deeper in the
network there is just one place where
you might use a linear activation
function G of Z equals Z and that's if
you are doing machine learning on a
regression problem so if Y is a real
number so for example if you're trying
to predict housing prices so Y is a it's
not 0 1 but it's a real number you know
anywhere from zero dollars is a price of
holes up to however expensive right
house of kin I guess maybe however can
be you know potentially millions of
dollars so however however much houses
cost in your data set but if Y takes on
these real values then it might be OK to
have a linear activation function here
so that your output Y hat is also a real
number going anywhere from minus
infinity to plus infinity but then the
hidden units should not use the new
activation functions they could use relu
or 10h or these you relu or maybe
something else so the one place you
might use a linear activation function
others usually in the output layer but
other than that using a linear
activation function in a fitting layer
except for some very special
circumstances relating to compression
that won't want to talk about using a
linear activation function is extremely
rare oh and of course today actually
predicting housing prices as you saw on
the week 1 video because housing prices
are all non-negative perhaps even then
you can use a value activation function
so that your outputs Y hat are all
greater than or equal to 0 so I hope
that gives you a sense of why having a
nonlinear activation function is a
critical part of neural networks next
we're going to start to talk about
gradient descent and to do that to set
up for discussion for gradient descent
in the next video I want to show you how
to estimate how to compute the slope of
the derivative of individual activation
functions so let's go on to the next
video