when you implement back-propagation for
your neural network you need to really
compute the slope or the derivative of
the activation functions so let's take a
look at our choices of activation
functions and how you can compute the
slope of these functions you can see
familiar sigmoid activation function and
so for any given value of z maybe this
value of z this function will have some
slope or some derivative corresponding
to if you draw a rule line there you
know the height over with there's no
triangle here so if G of Z is the
sigmoid function then the slope of the
function is e VZ G of Z and so we know
from calculators that the disss slope of
G of X and V and if you are familiar
with calculus and know how to take
derivatives if you take the derivative
of the sigmoid function it is possible
to show that it is equal to this formula
and again I'm not going to do the
calculus steps but if you're familiar
with calculus do for you to pause the
video and try to prove this yourself and
so this is equal to just G of Z times 1
minus G of Z so let's just sanity check
that this expression makes sense
first if Z is very large so say Z is
equal to 10 then G of Z will be close to
1 and so the formula we have on the Left
tells us that D DZ G of Z does be close
to G of Z which is equal to 1 times 1
minus 1 which is therefore very close to
0 and this isn't d correct because when
Z is very large the slope is close to 0
conversely of Z is equal to minus 10 so
there's no way out there then G of Z is
close to 0 so the following on the left
tells us d DZ G of Z will be close to G
of Z which is 0 times 1 line is 0 and so
this is also very close to 0 which is
correct
finally at Z is equal to 0
then G of Z is equal to 1/2 that's a
sigmoid function right here and so the
derivative is on equal to 1/2 times 1
minus 1/2 which is equal to 1/4 and that
actually is turns out to be the correct
value of the derivative or the slope of
this function when Z is equal to 0
finally just to introduce one more piece
of notation sometimes instead of writing
this thing the shorthand for the
derivative is G prime of Z so G prime of
Z in calculus the the little dash on top
is called prime but so G prime of Z is a
shorthand for the in calculus for the
derivative of the function of G with
respect to the input variable Z um and
then in a new network we have a equals G
of Z right equals this then this formula
also simplifies to a times 1 minus a so
sometimes the implementation you might
see something like G prime of Z equals a
times 1 minus a and that just refers to
you know the observation that G prime
which is used derivative is equal to
this over here and the advantage of this
formula is that if you've already
computed the value for a then by using
this expression you can very quickly
compute the value for the slope for G
prime s alright so that was the sigmoid
activation function let's now look at
the 10h activation function similar to
what we had previously the definition of
d DZ G of Z is the slope of G of Z as a
particular point of Z and if you look at
the formula for the hyperbolic tangent
function and if you know calculus you
can take derivatives and show that this
simplifies to this formula
and using the own shorthand we have
previously when we call this G prime of
Z you gain so if you want you can sanity
check that this formula make sense so
for example if Z is equal to 10 10 H of
Z will be very close to 1 this goes from
plus 1 to minus 1 and then G prime of Z
according to this formula will be about
1 minus 1 squared so during 3 closes
zero so that was a Z is very large the
slope is close to zero conversely a Z is
very small say Z is equal to minus 10
then 10 H of Z will be close to minus 1
and so G prime of Z will be close to 1
minus negative 1 squared so it's close
to 1 minus 1 which is also close to 0
and finally is equal to 0 then 10 H of Z
is equal to 0 and then the slope is
actually equal to 1 which is which
selection the slope point on Z is equal
to 0 so just to summarize if a is equal
to G of Z so if a is equal to this
challenge of Z then the derivative G
prime of Z is equal to 1 minus a squared
so once again if you've already computed
the value of a you can use this formula
to very quickly compute the derivative
as well finally here's how you compute
the derivatives for the value and
looky-loo activation functions for the
value g of z is equal to max of 0 comma
Z so the derivative is equal to you
turns out to be 0 if Z is less than 0
and 1 if Z is greater than 0 and is
actually our undefined
technically undefined the G is equal to
exactly 0 but um if you're implementing
this in software it might not be a
hundred percent mathematically correct
but the work just fine if you V is
exactly really zero if you set the
derivative to be equal to 1 or this had
to be 0 it kind of doesn't matter if
you're an excellent
nation technically G prime then becomes
what's called a sub gradient of the
activation function G of Z which is why
gradient descent still works but you can
think of it as that the chance of Z
being you know zero point exactly those
or those of those or zero is so small
that it almost doesn't matter what you
set the derivative to be equal to when Z
is equal to zero so in practice this is
what people implement for the derivative
of Z and finally if you are training on
your own network with the we here a Lou
activation function then G of Z is going
to be max of say 0.01 Z comma Z and so G
prime of Z is equal to 0.01 that Z is
less than 0 and 1 if Z is greater than 0
and once again the gradient is
technically not defined when Z is
exactly equal to 0 but some maybe
implement a piece of code that sets the
derivative or the assess G prime Z
either a 0.01 or to 1 either way it
doesn't really matter when Z is exactly
0 your co-workers so arms of these
formulas you should either compute the
slopes or the derivatives of your
activation assumptions now we have this
building blocks you're ready to see how
to implement gradient descent for your
neural network let's go onto the next
video to see that