in a previous video you saw how to
compute derivatives and implement
gradient descent with respect to just
one training example for religious
regression now we want to do it for Emma
training examples to get started let's
remind ourselves that the definition of
the cost function J cost function WP
which you care about is this average
right 1 over m sum from I equals 1 to M
you know the loss when your algorithm
output a I on the example why we're you
know AI is the prediction on the I've
trained example which is Sigma of Z I
which is equal to Sigma of W transpose X
plus B ok so what we show in the
previous slide is for any single
training example how to compute LD
derivatives when you have just one
training example great so d w1 d w2 and
d be with now the superscript I to
denote the corresponding values you get
if you are doing what we did on the
previous slide but just using the one
training example X I Y I I was using it
missing on either as well so now you
notice the overall cost functions is sum
was really the average because the 1
over m term of the individual losses so
it turns out that the derivative respect
to say w1 of the overall cost function
is also going to be the average of
derivatives respect to w1 of the
individual loss terms but previously we
have already shown how to compute this
term as say d w1 I right which we you
know on the previous slide show how the
computers on a single training example
so what you need to do is really compute
these own derivatives as we showed on
the previous training example and
average them and this will give you the
overall gradient that you can use to
implement
straight into scent so I know there was
a lot of details but let's take all of
this up and wrap this up into a concrete
algorithms and what you should implement
together logistic regression with
gradient descent working so just what
you can do let's initialize J equals 0
on DW 1 equals 0 DW 2 equals 0 DB equals
0 and what we're going to do is use a
for loop over the training set and
compute the derivatives to respect each
training example and then add them up
all right so see as we do it for I
equals 1 through m so M is the number of
training examples we compute CI equals W
transpose X I plus B armed the
prediction AI is equal to Sigma of zi
and then you know let's let's add up j j
plus equals y i long a I M plus 1 minus
y I log 1 minus AI and then put a
negative sign in front of the whole
thing and then as we saw earlier we have
d zi or it is equal to AI minus y i and
DW gets plus equals x1 i d zi b w2 plus
equals x i2 d zi or and i'm doing this
calculation assuming that you have just
be two features so the n is equal to 2
otherwise you do this for d w1 z w2 TW 3
and so on and GB plus equals V V I and I
guess that's the end of the for loop and
then finally having done this for all M
training examples you will still need to
divide by M because we're computing
averages so d w1
if I equals m DW to divide calls m DB
device equals M in all the complete
averages and so with all of these
calculations you've just computed the
derivative of the cost function J with
respect to e three parameters W 1 W 2
and B so the comment details what we're
doing we're using DW 1 + DW and DP
- as accumulators right so that after
this computation you know DW 1 is equal
to the derivative of your overall cost
function with respect to W 1 and
similarly for DW 2 and DV so notice that
DW 1 + DW to do not have a superscript I
because we're using them in this code as
accumulators to sum over the entire
training set whereas in contrast bzi
here this was on P Z with respect to
just one single training example that is
why that has a superscript I to refer to
the one training example either that's
computer on and so having finished all
these calculations to implement one step
of gradient descent you implement w1
gets updated as w1 - a learning rate
times d w1 w2 gives updates w2 one is
learning rate times d w2 and B gives
update as B - learning rate times EB
where PW 1 DW 2 + DB where you know as
computed and finally J here would also
be a correct value for your cost
function so everything on the slide
implements just one single step of
gradient descent and so you have to
repeat everything on this slide multiple
times in order to take multiple steps of
gradient descent in case these details
seem too complicated
again don't worry too much about it for
now hopefully all this will be clearer
when you go and implement this in D
programming assignment but it turns out
there are two weaknesses with the
calculation as with as with implemental
adhere which is that to implement
logistic regression this way you need to
write two for loops the first for loop
is a small loop over the M training
examples and the second for loop is a
for loop over all the features over here
right so in this example we just had two
features so n is 2 equal to 2 and X
equals 2 but if you have more features
you end up writing your DW 1 DW 2 and
you have similar computations for DW v
and so on down to DW n so seems like you
need to have a for loop over the
features over all n features
when you're implementing deep learning
algorithms you find that having explicit
for loops in your code makes your
algorithm run less efficiency and so in
the deep learning error would move to a
bigger and bigger data sets and so being
able to implement your algorithms
without using explicit for loops is
really important and will help you to
scale to much bigger data sets so it
turns out that there are set of
techniques called vectorization
techniques that allows you to get rid of
these explicit full loops in your code I
think in the pre deep learning era
that's before the rise of deep learning
vectorization was a nice to have you
could sometimes do it to speed a vehicle
and sometimes not but in the deep
learning era vectorization that is
getting rid of for loops like this and
like this has become really important
because we're more and more training on
very large datasets and so you really
need your code to be very efficient so
in the next few videos we'll talk about
vectorization and how to implement all
this without using even a single full
loop so of this I hope you have a sense
of how to intimate logistic regression
or gradient descent for logistic
regression on things will be clearer
when you implement the program exercise
but before actually doing the program
exercise let's first talk about
vectorization so then you can implement
this whole thing implement a single
iteration of gradient descent without
using any fall news