So let's scale up our example a bit.
They're using a convolutional neural
network architecture which is
known as ResNet-50.
ResNet-50 is a 50-layer
convolutional neural network
with a special property that we
are not strictly following the rule,
that there are only connections
between subsequent layers.
So ResNet is using so called residual
learning, the actual layers are skipping
some connections and connecting to more
downstream layers to improve performance.
But details on that is beyond
the scope of this course and
luckily this class already provides us
with a prepared and compiled model.
We import an image router and
some pre-imposed processing helpers.
But it's getting even better.
We are not only provided
with a prepared model but
we are also provided with
a already trained model.
So in this case we specify that
we want to obtain the weights
based on a training which has been
done on the image net data set.
So the image net data set is
a pre-classified database with over 14
million images, and over 27 classes,
and nearly 22,000 subclasses.
Obviously, training a 50-layer neural
network with 14 million images can
take quite some time.
So we're lucky that we
can just download it.
By the way,
this process is called transfer learning,
especially if you would further improve
and train the model with our data.
We will test this model with an elephant
which I found in the Internet.
We load this image and
scale it down to 224 by 224 pixels.
We turn this into a 3D array,
also known as a 3D tensor,
with 224 by 224 by 3 since we
are working with a colored image.
We now expand the shape to 1 by 224 by 224
by 3 because usually we are expecting or
we are throwing a bunch of
images at a neural network but
in this case we have only one,
so the first dimension is one.
Then we scale the image,
then we normalize the data to range
between minus one and plus one.
Now it's time to predict the elephant.
The output is a vector of size 1,000,
so we're getting
back a vector with class probabilities for
1,000 classes which is not very handy.
Therefore, we use 3D core predict method,
and we get back the extra class
labels as strings, in this case for
the three best classes.
Let's execute the and while it runs, let's
look at the image which we are using.
So this obviously is an elephant.
We download the elephant and
we rename it to elephant.jpeg
because this name we are using here.
So as you can see, with the probability
of 93%, this is an African elephant.
So this works pretty well.
Note that in the original example,
the authors used a different image, so
most likely an image
of an Indian elephant.
Let's try something else.
Let's try a bee.
Okay, this looks more like fly,
but let's see what happens.
Okay, this was a quite difficult example.
Even I thought this was a fly, me and
the neuron have not agreed on this.
So with a probability of 33% this is
a fly, and with 26%, this is a bee.
Anyway, I think you got the point and
you see how easy things are getting.
Especially if you are using all of your.