In some of the earlier videos,
I was talking about PCA as a compression
algorithm where you may have say,
1,000-dimensional data and compress
it to 100-dimensional feature vector.
Or have three-dimensional data and
compress it to a two-dimensional
representation.
So, if this is a compression algorithm,
there should be a way to go back
from this compressed representation
back to an approximation of your
original high-dimensional data.
So given zi, which may be 100-dimensional,
how do you go back to
your original representation,
xi which was maybe a 1000-dimensional.
In this video,
I'd like to describe how to do that.
In the PCA algorithm,
we may have an example like this, so
maybe that's my example x1, and
maybe that's my example x2.
And what we do is we take these examples,
and we project them onto this
one dimensional surface.
And then now we need to use a real number,
say z1, to specify the location of
these points after they've been projected
onto this one dimensional surface.
So, given the point z1, how can we go back
to this original two dimensional space?
In particular,
given the point z, which is R,
can we map this back to some
approximate representation x and
R2 of whatever the original
value of the data was?
So whereas z equals U reduce transpose x,
if you want to go in the opposite
direction, the equation for
that is, we're going to write x
approx equals U reduce, times z.
And again, just to check the dimensions,
here U reduce is going to be an n
by k dimensional vector, z is going
to be k by one dimensional vector.
So you multiply these out
that's going to be n by one, so
x approx is going to be
an n dimensional vector.
And so the intent of PCA, that is if the
square projection error is not too big,
is that this x approx
will be close to whatever
was the original value of x that you have
used to derive z in the first place.
To show a picture of what this looks like,
this is what it looks like.
What you get back of this procedure are
points that lie on the projection of that,
onto the green line.
So to take our early example, if we
started off with this value of x1, and
we got this value of z1, if you plug z1
through this formula to get x1 approx,
then this point here,
that would be x1 approx,
which is going to be in R2.
And similarly, if you do the same
procedure, this would be x2 approx.
And that's a pretty decent
approximation to the original data.
So that's how you go back from your
low dimensional representation z,
back to an uncompressed
representation of the data.
We get back an approximation
to your original data x.
And we also call this process
reconstruction of the original data
where we think of trying to
reconstruct the original value of x
from the compressed representation.
So, given an unlabeled data set, you now
know how to apply PCA and take your high
dimensional features x and map that to
this lower-dimensional representation z.
And from this video hopefully you now also
know how to take these low-representation
z and map it back up to an approximation
of your original high-dimensional data.
Now that you know how to implement and
apply PCA, what I'd like to do
next is talk about some of the mechanics
of how to actually use PCA well.
And in particular in the next video,
I'd like to talk about how to choose k,
which is how to choose the dimension
of the reduced representation vector z.