We've all been hearing that deep
neural networks work really well for
a lot of problems, and it's not just that
they need to be big neural networks,
is that specifically, they need to be
deep or to have a lot of hidden layers.
So why is that?
Let's go through a couple examples and
try to gain some intuition for
why deep networks might work well.
So first,
what is a deep network computing?
If you're building a system for
face recognition or
face detection, here's what a deep
neural network could be doing.
Perhaps you input a picture of a face then
the first layer of the neural network
you can think of as maybe being
a feature detector or an edge detector.
In this example, I'm plotting what a
neural network with maybe 20 hidden units,
might be kind of compute on this image.
So the 20 hidden units visualize
by these little square boxes.
So for example, this little visualization
represents a hidden unit is
trying to figure out if where
the edges of that orientation in DMH.
And maybe this hidden unit
maybe trying to figure
out where are the horizontal
edges in this image.
And when we talk about convolutional
networks in a later course,
this particular visualization
will make a bit more sense.
But the form, you can think of the first
layer of the neural network as look at
the picture and try to figure out
where are the edges in this picture.
Now, let's think about where the edges
in this picture by grouping together
pixels to form edges.
It can then de-detect the edges and group
edges together to form parts of faces.
So for example, you might have a low
neuron trying to see if it's finding an I,
or a different neuron trying
to find that part of the nose.
And so by putting together lots of edges,
it can start to detect
different parts of faces.
And then, finally, by putting
together different parts of faces,
like an eye or a nose or an ear or
a chin, it can then try to recognize or
detect different types of faces.
So intuitively, you can think of the
earlier layers of the neural network as
detecting simple functions, like edges.
And then composing them together in
the later layers of a neural network so
that it can learn more and
more complex functions.
These visualizations will make more sense
when we talk about convolutional nets.
And one technical detail
of this visualization,
the edge detectors are looking in
relatively small areas of an image,
maybe very small regions like that.
And then the facial detectors you can look
at maybe much larger areas of image but
the main addition while you take away
from this is just finding simple things
like edges and then building them up.
Composing them together to detect
more complex things like an iron and
then composing those together to
find more even complex things.
And this type of simple to complex
hierarchical representation,
or compositional representation,
applies in other types of data than
images and face recognition as well.
For example, if you're trying to
build a speech recognition system,
it's hard to revisualize speech but
if you input an audio clip then maybe
the first level of a neural network might
learnt to detect low level audio wave form
features, such as is this toe going up?
Is it going down?
Is it white noise or
slithering sound like [SOUND].
And what is the pitch?
When it comes to that, detect low
level wave form features like that.
And then by composing
low level wave forms,
maybe you'll learn to detect
basic units of sound.
In linguistics they call phonemes.
But, for example, in the word cat,
the C is a phoneme, the A is a phoneme,
the T is another phoneme.
But learns to find maybe
the basic units of sound and
then composing that together maybe
learn to recognize words in the audio.
And then maybe compose those together,
in order to recognize entire phrases or
sentences.
So deep Internet work with multiple hidden
layers might be able to have the earlier
layers learn these lower
level simple features and
then have the later deeper layers then put
together the simpler things it's detected
in order to detect more complex things
like recognize specific words or
even phrases or sentences.
The uttering in order to
carry out speech recognition.
And what we see is that whereas the other
layers are computing, what seems like
relatively simple functions of the input
such as right at the edges, by the time
you get deep in the network you can
actually do surprisingly complex things.
Such as detect faces or
detect words or phrases or sentences.
Some people like to make an analogy
between deep neural networks and
the human brain, where we believe,
or neuroscientists believe,
that the human brain also starts off
detecting simple things like edges in what
your eyes see then builds those
up to detect more complex
things like the faces that you see.
I think analogies between
deep learning and
the human brain are sometimes
a little bit dangerous.
But there is a lot of truth to, this being
how we think that human brain works and
that the human brain probably
detects simple things like edges and
then put them together to from more and
more complex objects and so that
has served as a loose form of inspiration
for some people learning as well.
We'll see a bit more
about the human brain or
about the biological brain in
the lead of video this week.
The other piece of intuition
about why deep networks seem to
work well is the following.
So this result comes from circuit
theory of which pertains the thinking
about what types of functions you can
compute with different logic case.
So informally, their functions compute
with a relatively small but deep neural
network and by small I mean the number
of hidden units is relatively small.
But if you try to compute the same
function with a shallow network,
so hidden layers,
then you might require exponentially
more hidden units to compute.
So let me just give you one example and
illustrate this a bit informally.
But let's say you're trying to
compute the exclusive [INAUDIBLE] or
the parity of all your input features.
So you're trying to compute X1,
XOR, X2, XOR,
X3, XOR, up to Xn if you have n or
n X features.
So if you build in XOR free like this,
so for us it computes the XOR of X1 and
X2, then take X3 and
X4 and compute their XOR.
And technically, if you're just using
ends or not gauge, you might need
couple layers to compute the XOR
function rather than just one layer, but
with a relatively small circuit,
you can compute the XOR, and so on.
And then you can build,
really, an XOR tree like so,
until eventually, you have a circuit here
that outputs, well, lets call this Y.
The outputs of Y hat equals Y.
The exclusive or
the parity of all these input bits.
So to compute XOR, the definite left
network will be on the order of log N.
We'll just have an XOR tree.
So the number of nodes or
the number of circuit components or
the number of gates in this
network is not that large.
You don't need that many gates in
order to compute the exclusive OR.
But now, if you are not allowed to
use a neural network with north pole
hidden layers with, in this case,
order log and hidden layers,
if you're forced to compute this
function with just one hidden layer,
so you have all these things going into,
so the hidden units.
And then these things then output Y.
Then in order to compute this
XOR function, this hidden layer
will need to be exponentially large,
because essentially,
you need to exhaustively enumerate our
2 to the N possible configurations.
So on the order of 2 to the N,
possible configurations of the input
bits that result in the exclusive
[INAUDIBLE] being either 1 or 0.
So you end up needing a hidden layer
that is exponentially large in
the number of bits.
I think technically, you could do this
with 2 to the N minus 1 hidden units.
But that's the older 2 to the N processes
explanation larger the number of bits.
So I hope this gives a sense that
there are mathematical functions,
that are much easier to compute with deep
networks than with shallow networks.
Actually, I personally found the result
from circuit theory less useful for
gaining intuitions, but
just one of the results that people often
cite when explaining the value of
having very deep representations.
Now, in addition to this reasons for
preferring deep neural
networks to be roughly on,
is I think the other reasons the term deep
learning has taken off is just branding.
This things just we call neural
networks belong to hidden layers, but
the phrase deep learning is just
a great brand, it's just so deep.
So I think that once that term caught on
that really new networks rebranded or
new networks with many
hidden layers rebranded,
help to capture the popular
imagination as well.
They regard as the PR branding
deep networks do work well.
Sometimes people go overboard and
insist on using tons of hidden layers.
But when I'm starting out a new problem,
I'll often really start out with
neuro-logistic regression then
try something with one or
two hidden layers and
use that as a hyper parameter.
Use that as a parameter or hyper parameter
that you tune in order to try to find
the right depth for your neural network.
But over the last several years there has
been a trend toward people finding that
for some applications, very, very deep
neural networks here with maybe many
dozens of layers sometimes, can sometimes
be the best model for a problem.
So that's it for the intuitions for
why deep learning seems to work well.
Let's now take a look at the mechanics
of how to implement not just front
propagation, but also back propagation.