so what a deep learning have to do the
brain at the risk of giving away the
punchline I would say not a whole lot
but let's take a quick look at why
people keep making the analogy between
deep learning and the human brain when
you implement a neural network this is
what you do for prop and back prop and I
think because it's been difficult to
convey intuitions about what these
equations are doing really great and
descends on a very complex function the
analogy that is like the brain has
become really an oversimplified
explanation for what this is doing but
the simplicity of this makes it you know
kind of seductive for people to just say
it publicly as well as the media to
report it and certainly called the
popular imagination and there is a very
loose analogy between let's say a
logistic regression unit with a sigmoid
activation function and here's a cartoon
of a single neuron in the brain in this
picture of a biological neuron on this
neuron which is a cell in your brain
receives electric signals from you know
other neurons mu X 1 X 2 X 3 or maybe
from other neurons a 1 a 2 a 3 there's a
simple thresholded computation and then
if this neuron fires it sends a pulse of
electricity down the axon down this long
wire perhaps to other neurons so there
is a very simplistic analogy between a
single logistic unit between a single
neuron and network and a biological
neuron like that shown on a right but I
think that today even neuroscientists
have almost no idea what even a single
neuron is doing a single neuron appears
to be much more complex than we are able
to characterize with neuroscience and
while some of what is doing is a little
bit like logistic regression there's
still a lot about what even a single
neuron does that no one there no human
today understands for example exactly
how neurons in the human brain learn
this is still a very mysterious process
and it's completely unclear today
whether the human brain uses an
algorithm does anything like back
propagation or gradient descent
or if there's some fundamentally
different learning principle that the
human brain uses so when I think of deep
learning I think of it as being very
good and learning very flexible
functions very complex functions to
learn X to Y mappings to learn
input-output mappings in supervised
learning and whereas D is like the brain
analogy maybe that was useful once I
think the field has moved to the point
where that analogy is breaking down and
I tend not to use that analogy much
anymore so that's it so neural networks
and their brain I do think that maybe
the field of computer vision has taken a
bit more inspiration from the human
brains and other disciplines that also
apply to learning but I personally use
the analogy you know to the human brain
less than I used to so that's it for
this video
you now know how to implement for prop
and back prop in gradient descent even
for deep neural networks best of luck
with the pro exercise and I look forward
to sharing more of these ideas of you in
the second course