Welcome back. Today, we're starting our PyTorch introductory sessions.
What is PyTorch?
PyTorch is a new Deep Learning Framework which is highly dynamic in tons of ways.
This framework is is a rising star on the sky of Deep Learning and very,
very popular especially by research.
But first of all,
we just going to download and install
PyTorch in our Watson Data Science Experience workbook.
Just go to pytorch.org then scroll down to the Get Started section and then here,
you have a selection.
For our Watson Data Science Experience notebooks,
we need operating system Linux,
we need package manager pip,
and we select Python 2.7.
And we don't select CUDA because,
at least at the moment,
we don't have GPU acceleration there.
And then you have here this two lines of code.
Just copy them and go to your Jupyter Notebook and then you can paste them,
but you have to place exclamation marks at the beginning of the line before pip.
And then you just execute this,
and I don't execute it because I have already installed PyTorch in my environment.
And then you can test.
If you import PyTorch,
you see everything went mostly, everything is fine.
So, see you then in the next session.
Then, we are going to look at the important packages
of PyTorch and do some interesting things. Bye-bye.