Welcome back. Last time,
we have discussed the dimensionality of the tensors.
Today, we're going to have a quick look at
the mathematical operations with tensors like multiplication,
addition, and so on.
First, we define two tensors of size three.
It's a one tensor one, two, three,
second one, four, five, six,
and then, we can multiply tensors.
So, if we call "matmul", let's execute.
So we see, we are printing out of the tensors,
we have the first float tensor of size three,
second one of the same size,
and the result of matmul is scalar.
Why it so? Because matmul is actually
scalar multiplication which we know from linear algebra.
So, the second one is
interesting operation which we can do with tensors is concatenation.
First, we define two tensors from
random numbers of size two and then,
we are calling "torch.cat", "torch.cat".
It will concatenate tensors and by default if we don't specify the axis,
it will stock the tensors.
Maybe we should execute this.
All right now, so you can see that we have here one tensor
which has two rows and five columns of size two by five.
We have second tensor which have three rows, five columns,
three by five, and if you call cat concatenate,
it will stock this two matrices or two tensors
and we have them a tensor of size five by five.
Another way is to concatenate tensors column wise.
For this, we have to specify axis.
So if we specify axis of one as a second parameter,
it will align the tensors,
so it will concatenate column wise.
So, we can see how it looks like.
So, we have one tensor of size two by three,
second one of size two by five,
and if we call cat with axis of one,
we will get a tensor of size two by eight.
So, if we define wrong number,
it will not be able to execute this concatenation,
I mean wrong number of rows for example.
Let's define the second tensor of size three by five.
Instead of two by five,
and then we execute this,
so we get error, inconsistent tensor sizes.
It's pretty simple.
Now, we're going to look how to reshape the tensors.
It's actually a variation which we usually need.
Let's assume we have RGB images.
We have 64,000 images which we can for example,
analyze with our convolutional neural network.
And here, if we want to reshape this tensor,
so initially we have a tensor of shape (64,000,
3, 28, 28) what could it be?
It could be here on the second position,
it could be number of color channels, three,
it's actually a usual way to define images.
And the last two,
we'll use 28, 28,
this is the image size.
Now, let's assume we have to reshape the whole tensor or this is a tensor,
actually torch number, we'll create a tensor,
we'll have to reshape it,
and we want to introduce a batch size for example.
So, we want to see how many batches we can construct out of 64,000 images.
So, we have here on the first position,
we will define the batch size.
Now, we can left unchanged the number of
color channels which is three and the image size 28, 28.
But here, we can infer the second dimension,
we can left unfilled,
so with minus one,
and it will cost the pytorch will automatically infer
the correct second dimension.
It takes some time because it calls a random number.
Sometimes it takes a moment.
So now, we see batch size 32 and then it has insert 2,000, it's great.
So, if you multiplied 2,000 with 32,
you will get exactly 64,000.
Okay. I hope you enjoyed the session and see you next time.
Enjoy. Bye bye.