All right, now that we've
demonstrated what we intend to do,
let's go ahead and do it.
Let's go ahead and write a model
classifier in Keras, save the model,
input that model into DL4J and
execute it on Spark.
So first I'm going to
create a new notebook.
And I'm going to call this Coursera for
the Coursera example, and create.
So I've created a Python
notebook with Spark.
So the first thing we're
going to need to do,
is we're going to need to
download our data file.
And that data file is right here.
So, I'm going to run wget and
grab that file from this GitHub repo.
When I've done that, ls should show it.
Now that we see that it's there,
let's go ahead and take a look at it.
So we see the data file is
as I described previously.
A measurement, another measurement,
another measurement,
another measurement and
then the class of the iris.
And we some irises in class 0,
irises in class 1,
irises in class 2.
So now we have the data file.
Let's build a model.
So we're going to be using Keras so
there's some imports we need to include.
And let's add those here in this cell.
All right, so we're going to import NumPy,
import Pandas and some additional imports.
We're going to set a random seed for
reproducibility.
I'll put some new lines there so we get
the data up in the middle of the screen.
Now we're going to read
that iris.txt file and
create a data set of our features and
a data set of our labels.
So we're going to read the file, iris.txt,
there is no header so every line is data.
And then the x-data set is
going to be our features.
So the first four columns are going to
be interpreted as floats.
And the last one is an integer,
in this case.
This code would also work
if it was text labels,
because we transform
that in the next example.
So the last field here
are these integers for
the, Labels, for the classes.
So let's take that dataset,
the y dataset, the labels.
And encode that using dummy encoding
also called one-hot encoding.
Basically we have three classes so
that will be an array of three values,
they'll all be zero's except for one.
So class one will be 1,0,0,
class two will be 0,1,0.
And if you need to demonstrate that,
or explore that a little bit you can
go ahead and short circuit this code and
print out dummy wide to the screen.
Now let's build our model.
So we're going to use
a simple sequential model,
a feed-forward neural net, right here.
So our input has four features,
so that defines our input layer.
And our output has three classes,
so that defines our output layer.
So, a single hidden layer neural network,
feed forward neural network.
Now let's pass it our data
So we want to say given this model,
feed it our features,
have it trained towards the goal
of predicting the class.
Which is stored in dummy_y.
We're going to run it for 20 epics,
that's 20 full passes through the data.
And we're going to look at five examples
per forward pass before
we update our weights.
And the next thing we want to do is,
we want to save the model.
So when the model completes, we want
to write the model to a h5 archive,
which is how Keras saves its model.
So that's the full collection
of our Python code.
Let's go ahead and execute that sum.
Just a warning about the changes upcoming.
Lets us know we are using
the Tensorflow backend.
And there we see as it
goes through each epic.
We see it starts off with
the accuracy of .66, largely random.
And then it trains and improves.
And when it's done we should see,
That data file.
So if we run ls.
We should see that it's
written my_model.h5.
Excellent, so we've run our Keras model,
it trained to an accuracy of 84.
And now we're going to ship that
saved model into that DL4J code.
So the first thing we need to do is we
need to download that compiled jar,
that has the DL4J code to load the model.
And you're welcome to
go to this git-repo and
take a complete look at that code
This is larger, so
it might take a little bit of time.
While that's downloading I'm going to show
you the code that we're going to execute.
So in order to execute this code, we're
going to do what we've done, similar.
We need to execute a spark-submit script.
And so spark-submit is available here.
And then this is just a line
continuation characters.
So I don't have really long lines.
So the data science experience
environment provides a environmental
variable that points us
to this spark-submit.
Spark-submit allows us to specify
the class that we'd like to execute.
And that's right here.
So I want to run
the KerasImportCSVSparkRunner.
In order to get the data files uploaded
to Spark, we use this files command.
So that just says, take these files,
ship them into Spark and make them
available in the working directory
of all of our workers for this job.
So they'll be available for any of
the workers that are working on this job
Specify we want to submit it to
the Spark Master that's defined in
the environmental variable in the data
science experience as $MASTER.
And then we want to ship,
This JAR file, so
this is the JAR file
that contains this class.
All right?
So this is the class we're
going to execute.
This is the JAR file
that contains this class.
This class, when it runs, is going to load
the model that I just saved in Keras.
And when it loads that model,
it's going to do an evaluation against
the data found in this iris.text file.
So now we just need to tell
our KerasImportCSVSparkRunner
class the parameters
that it needs to execute.
When I run distributed training in Spark,
I can specify the batch size per worker.
This is just like specifying the
batch-size on a non-distributed process.
How many examples to view
before we update our weights?
And note that these options take a single
dash whereas there's a previous options to
take a double dash.
But the main differentiators,
they come after the jar file.
So these are the options that will be
passed to this class when it's executed.
The class KerasImportCSVSparkRunner,
has an option where I could specify
that I wanted it to train, in Spark.
I'm setting that to false.
We're just going to do validation to
verify that the network has imported
correctly and
we're getting expected results.
As I've said previously,
this is a generic example.
So you could train it on
a classification problem with
10 classes in a CSV file where the index
lable was perhaps 10 or 11 or 12.
All right?
So you specify which column is the label
and how many labels there are.
So I encourage you to try
perhaps your own example.
The other option that we want to pass to,
KerasImportCSVSparkRunner is
the name of the model.
Right?
So this is the Keras model file let's
specify here and here.
So here we're saying ship this
model file up into Spark.
And here we're saying to this
class load that model and
create a DL4J model from that
saved Keras configuration.
Similar for the data file.
We need to specify that we want.
Once we've taken our model,
loaded it into DL4J,
configured a Spark training master,
configured how to read the data file,
that it goes ahead and
reads that and does an evaluation.
And that's it.
So this command, this shell command
started with the exclamation point will
submit that jar right there to Spark.
And when that charge is shipped to Spark,
it'll say run this class.
And that class will load
this model specified here.
That model will evaluate this file, and
these are configuration options
that say how to read that file.
And this option just says, we're not
going to train, just run an evaluation.
So verify that our data file
up above has downloaded.
It has, let's go ahead and run this code.
It may take some time.
Understand we're shipping
the jar to the Spark workers.
And the Data Science Experience does
provide the access to the Spark
history server.
There we go.
So we're getting some logging output.
But yeah, you can go take a look at the
history of your jobs in the Spark history
server, by going to
the environment of your notebook.
Let's just wait for
that to make some progress.
There we go.
Spark is very verbose.
So what we're looking for
is the code that we're executing
does an evaluation at the end.
And we're looking for that evaluation, so
we'll see it like a truth table, we'll
class one was classified as class one.
X number of times class
two is classified as, so
it'll show us the positives,
show us the false positives and
negatives etc.
Show us how well the model did basically.
So there we see the output
from one of the workers.
So we some information about memory
use as the workers load the RDD or
their subset of the RDD.
So that they can process it.
Now we see some farther progress.
Excellent!
So it completed.
Similarly if we scrolled up and
saw the accuracy of the Python example,
we see similar accuracy, 82%.
We could've trained it further.
I just ran it through 20 epochs, just so
it started to make some progress.
So it did good with class 0,
class 1, about 50-50.
On class two it got correct.
So it's having a little bit of trouble
with probably the middle class right?
Or actually more accurate it looks like
one is similar to two in some way and
it hasn't quite solved that relation yet.
You could have trained it further and
I believe it will get to higher accuracy.
But we see here accuracy of 82, and
if we scroll up to where we executed
our Python, we see very similar accuracy.
So there you have it.
A full, end to end example of
building a model in Keras,
in the data science experience.
Saving that model into
the data science experience.
And loading that model into
DL4J to execute it on Spark in
the IBM's data science experience.
Thank you.