In the third course of this sequence of
five courses, you saw how error analysis
can help you focus your time on doing
the most useful work for your project.
Now, beam search is
an approximate search algorithm,
also called a heuristic search algorithm.
And so it doesn't always output
the most likely sentence.
It's only keeping track of B equals 3 or
10 or 100 top possibilities.
So what if beam search makes a mistake?
In this video, you'll learn how error
analysis interacts with beam search and
how you can figure out whether it is
the beam search algorithm that's causing
problems and worth spending time on.
Or whether it might be your RNN
model that is causing problems and
worth spending time on.
Let's take a look at how to do
error analysis with beam search.
Let's use this example of Jane
visite l'Afrique en septembre.
So let's say that in your
machine translation dev set,
your development set,
the human provided this translation and
Jane visits Africa in September,
and I'm going to call this y*.
So it is a pretty good
translation written by a human.
Then let's say that when you run beam
search on your learned RNN model and
your learned translation model,
it ends up with this translation,
which we will call y-hat,
Jane visited Africa last September,
which is a much worse translation
of the French sentence.
It actually changes the meaning,
so it's not a good translation.
Now, your model has two main components.
There is a neural network model,
the sequence to sequence model.
We shall just call this your RNN model.
It's really an encoder and a decoder.
And you have your beam search algorithm,
which you're running
with some beam width b.
And wouldn't it be nice if you
could attribute this error,
this not very good translation,
to one of these two components?
Was it the RNN or really the neural
network that is more to blame, or
is it the beam search algorithm,
that is more to blame?
And what you saw in the third
course of the sequence is that
it's always tempting to collect more
training data that never hurts.
So in similar way, it's always tempting
to increase the beam width that never
hurts or pretty much never hurts.
But just as getting more
training data by itself might not
get you to the level of
performance you want.
In the same way,
increasing the beam width by itself might
not get you to where you want to go.
But how do you decide whether or
not improving the search algorithm
is a good use of your time?
So just how you can break
the problem down and
figure out what's actually
a good use of your time.
Now, the RNN, the neural network,
what was called RNN really means
the encoder and the decoder.
It computes P(y given x).
So for example, for
a sentence, Jane visits Africa
in September,
you plug in Jane visits Africa.
Again, I'm ignoring upper versus
lowercase now, right, and so on.
And this computes P(y given x).
So it turns out that
the most useful thing for
you to do at this point is to
compute using this model to compute
P(y* given x) as well as to compute
P(y-hat given x) using your RNN model.
And then to see which
of these two is bigger.
So it's possible that the left side
is bigger than the right hand side.
It's also possible that P(y*) is less
than P(y-hat) actually, or less than or
equal to, right?
Depending on which of these two cases
hold true, you'd be able to more
clearly ascribe this particular error,
this particular bad translation
to one of the RNN or the beam search
algorithm being had greater fault.
So let's take out the logic behind this.
Here are the two sentences
from the previous slide.
And remember,
we're going to compute P(y* given x) and
P(y-hat given x) and
see which of these two is bigger.
So there are going to be two cases.
In case 1,
P(y* given x) as output by the RNN
model is greater than P(y-hat given x).
What does this mean?
Well, the beam search
algorithm chose y-hat, right?
The way you got y-hat was you had
an RNN that was computing P(y given x).
And beam search's job was to try to find
a value of y that gives that arg max.
But in this case,
y* actually attains a higher value for
P(y given x) than the y-hat.
So what this allows you to conclude is
beam search is failing to actually give
you the value of y that maximizes
P(y given x) because the one
job that beam search had was to find
the value of y that makes this really big.
But it chose y-hat,
the y* actually gets a much bigger value.
So in this case, you could conclude
that beam search is at fault.
Now, how about the other case?
In case 2, P(y* given x) is less than or
equal to P(y-hat given x), right?
And then either this or
this has gotta be true.
So either case 1 or
case 2 has to hold true.
What do you conclude under case 2?
Well, in our example,
y* is a better translation than y-hat.
But according to the RNN,
P(y*) is less than P(y-hat),
so saying that y* is a less
likely output than y-hat.
So in this case,
it seems that the RNN model is
at fault and it might be worth
spending more time working on the RNN.
There's some subtleties here pertaining to
length normalizations
that I'm glossing over.
There's some subtleties pertaining
to length normalizations that I'm
glossing over.
And if you are using some
sort of length normalization,
instead of evaluating these probabilities,
you should be evaluating the optimization
objective that takes into
account length normalization.
But ignoring that complication for now,
in this case, what this tells you is that
even though y* is a better translation,
the RNN ascribed y* in lower probability
than the inferior translation.
So in this case,
I will say the RNN model is at fault.
So the error analysis
process looks as follows.
You go through the development set and
find the mistakes that the algorithm
made in the development set.
And so in this example, let's say that
P(y* given x) was 2 x 10 to the -10,
whereas, P(y-hat given x)
was 1 x 10 to the -10.
Using the logic from the previous slide,
in this case, we see that
beam search actually chose y-hat,
which has a lower probability than y*.
So I will say beam search is at fault.
So I'll abbreviate that B.
And then you go through
a second mistake or
second bad output by the algorithm,
look at these probabilities.
And maybe for the second example,
you think the model is at fault.
I'm going to abbreviate
the RNN model with R.
And you go through more examples.
And sometimes the beam search is at fault,
sometimes the model is at fault,
and so on.
And through this process, you can then
carry out error analysis to figure out
what fraction of errors are due to
beam search versus the RNN model.
And with an error analysis process like
this, for every example in your dev sets,
where the algorithm gives a much worse
output than the human translation,
you can try to ascribe the error
to either the search algorithm or
to the objective function, or
to the RNN model that generates
the objective function that beam
search is supposed to be maximizing.
And through this, you can try to figure
out which of these two components is
responsible for more errors.
And only if you find that beam search
is responsible for a lot of errors,
then maybe is we're working hard
to increase the beam width.
Whereas in contrast, if you find
that the RNN model is at fault,
then you could do a deeper layer of
analysis to try to figure out if you want
to add regularization, or
get more training data, or
try a different network architecture,
or something else.
And so a lot of the techniques that
you saw in the third course in
the sequence will be applicable there.
So that's it for
error analysis using beam search.
I found this particular error analysis
process very useful whenever you have
an approximate optimization algorithm,
such as beam search
that is working to optimize some sort of
objective, some sort of cost function
that is output by a learning algorithm,
such as a sequence-to-sequence model or
a sequence-to-sequence RNN that we've
been discussing in these lectures.
So with that, I hope that you'll be more
efficient at making these types of models
work well for your applications.