Hi Yann, you've been such a leader for
Deep Learning for so long,
thanks a lot for doing this with us.
>> Well, thanks for
having me.
>> So,
you've been working on neural nets for
a long time.
I would love to hear your personal story
of how you got started in AI, how did you
networking with neural networks?
>> So, I was always interested in
intelligence, in general,
the origins of intelligence in humans.
Got me interested into human
evolution when I was a kid.
>> That was in France?
>> It was in France, yeah.
I was in middle school or something and
I was interested in technology,
space, etc.
My favorite movie was
2001: A Space Odyssey.
You had intelligent machines,
space travel, and
human evolution as kind of the themes
that was what I was fascinated by.
And the concept of intelligent machines
I think really kind of appealed to me.
And then I studied electrical engineering.
And when I was at school, I was maybe
in second year of engineering school,
I stumbled on a book,
which was actually a philosophy book.
It was a debate between Noam Chomsky,
the computational linguist at MIT,
and Jean Piaget who is
a cognitive psychologist sort
of psychology of child
development in Switzerland.
And it was basically a debate
between nature and nurture,
where Chomsky arguing for the fact that
language has a lot of innate structure,
and Piaget saying a lot of it is learned,
and etc.
And on the side of Piaget was
a transcription of a person who,
each of these guys sort of brought their
teams of people to argue for their side.
And on the side of Piaget was
Seymour Papert from MIT, who had worked
on the perceptron model, one of
the first machines capable of running.
And I never heard of the perceptron,
and I read this article that say,
machine capable of running,
that sounds wonderful.
And so I started going to several
university libraries and searching for
everything I could find that talked about
the perceptron and realized there was
a lot of papers from the 50s, but
it kind of stopped at the end of the 60s,
with a book that was co-authored
by the same Seymour Papert.
>> What year was this?
>> So this was in 1980,
roughly?
>> Right.
>> And so I did a couple of projects with
some of the math professor in my school
on kind of neural nets, essentially.
But there was no one there I could
talk to who had worked on this,
because the field basically had
disappeared in the meantime, right?
Since 1980, nobody was working on this.
And experimented with this a little bit,
writing kind of simulation software of
various kinds, reading about neuroscience.
When I finished my engineering studies,
I studied chip design.
I'm good at site design at the time, so
it's something completely different.
And when I finished I really
wanted to do research on this and
I figured out already that at the time
the important question was how you train
neural nets with multiple layers.
It was pretty clear in the literature
of the 60s that that was the important
question that had been left unsolved and
their idea of hierarchy and everything.
I'd read Fukushima's article
on the neocognitron, right?
Which was this sort of hierarchical
architecture very similar to now what we
now call convolutional nets, but without
really backprop style learning algorithms.
And I met people who were in
a small independent club in France.
They were interested in what they
called at the time, Automata Networks.
And they gave me a couple papers,
the people on functional networks
which is not very popular anymore.
But it's the first associative memories
with neural net and that paper can revive
the interest of some research committees
into neural net in the early 80s.
Where by mostly physicists and
condense matter physicists and
a few psychologists,
it was still not okay for engineers and
computer scientists to
talk about neural nets.
And they also should be another
paper that had just been distributed
as a pre-print, whose title was
Optimal Perceptual Inference.
And this was the first paper on
Boltzmann machines by Geoff Hinton and
Terry Sejnowski.
It was talking about hidden units.
It was talking about, basically,
the part of learning,
multilayer neural nets are more
capable than just classifiers.
So I said,
I need to meet these people [LAUGH].
>> Wow.
>> Because they're only
interested in the right problem.
And a couple of years later,
after I started my PhD, I participated in
a workshop in Le Juch that was organized
by the people I was working with.
And Terry was one of
the speakers at the workshop, so
I met him at that time.
>> It was like early 80s now.
>> This is 1985, early 1985.
So I met Terry Sejnowski in 1985 in
the workshop in France in Le Juch and
a lot of people were there, founders
of early neural net, jump up field and,
a lot of people working on theoretical
neuroscience and stuff like that.
It was a fascinating workshop.
I met also, a couple of people from Bell
Labs who eventually hired me at Bell Labs,
but this was several years
before I finished my PhD.
So I talked to Terry Sejnowski and I was
telling him about what I was working on
which was some version
of backprop at the time.
This is before backprop was a paper and
Terry was working on net talk at the time.
This was before the Rumelhart,
Hinton, Williams paper on
backprop had been published.
But he was friends with Geoff,
this information was circulating,
so he was already working on trying
to make this work for net talk,
but he didn't tell me.
>> I see.
>> And he went back to US and
told Geoff there is some kid in France
who's working on the same stuff
we're working on.
>> I see.
>> [LAUGH] And then a few months later,
in June, there was another conference in
France where Geoff was a keynote speaker.
And he gave a talk on Boltzmann machines.
Of course,
he was working on the backprop paper.
And he gave this talk, and
then there was 50 people around
him who wanted to talk to him.
And the first thing he
said to the organizer is,
do you know this guy, Yann LeCun?
And it's because he had read my paper
in the proceedings that was written
in French.
And he could sort of read French and
he could see the math and
he could figure out what sort of backprop,
and so we had lunch together and
that's how we became friends.
>> I see, well.
>> [LAUGH]
>> So that's because multiple groups
independently reinvented or
invented backprop pretty much.
>> Right, well, we realized that the whole
idea with Chain Rule or what the optimal
control people call the joint state
method which is really the context in
which backprop was really invented.
This in context of optimal
control back in the early 60s.
This idea that you could use graded
descent basically with multiple stages
is what backprop really is and that popped
up in various contexts at various times.
And but I think the Rumelhart,
Hinton, Williams paper is
the one that popularized it.
>> I see, yeah, no, cool, yeah.
And then fast forward a few years,
you wound up at AT&T Bell Labs,
where you invented, among many things, the
net, which we talk about in the course.
And I remember when way back,
I was a summer intern at AT&T Bell Labs,
where I worked with Michael Kerns and
a few others, and
of hearing about your work even back then.
So tell me more about your AT&T,
the net, experience.
>> Okay, so what happened is,
I actually started working on
convolutional net when I was A postdoc,
University of Toronto, chief intern.
I did the first experiment,
I wrote the code there, and
I did the first experiments
there that showed that,
if you had a very small data set.
The data set I was training on, there
was no or anything like that back then.
So I drew a bunch of
characters with my mouse.
I had an Amiga, a personal computer,
which was the best computer ever.
And I drew a bunch of characters and
then used that.
I did augmentation to kind of increase it,
and
then used that as a way
to test performance.
And I compared things like
fully connected nets,
locally connected nets
without shared weights.
And then shared weight networks.
Which was basically the first comment.
And that worked really well for relatively
small data sets, could show that you get
better performance and no over-training
with conventional architecture.
And when I go to Bell Labs
in October 1988,
the first thing I did was first,
scale up the network,
because we had faster computers a few
months before I go to Bell Labs.
My boss at the time, Larry Jackal,
who became a department head of
said we should order a computer for
you before you come.
Where do you want?
I say well, here Toronto,
there is which was the stuff.
It'd be great if we had one.
And they ordered one and
I had one for myself.
At University of Toronto it was one for
the entire department, right?
One just for me, right?
And so Larry told me he said, you know at
Bell Labs you don't get famous by saving
money.
>> [LAUGH]
>> So that was awesome, and they had been
working already for
awhile on character recognition.
They had this enormous data set called
USDS that had 5,000 training samples.
[LAUGH] And so immediately I trained a
net, which was in the net one, basically.
And trained it on this data set and
got really good results,
better results than the other methods.
They had tried on it, and that other
people had tried on it is that so
that, we knew we had
something fairly early on.
This was within three months
of me joining Bell Labs.
And so that was the first
version of commercial net where
we had a convolution with stride,
and we did not have separate and
pulling layers.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So each convolution was actually
directly.
And the reason for
this is that we just could not afford to
have a convolution at every location.
There was just too much computation.
>> I see.
>> [COUGH] So, the second version had
a separate convolution and
pulling the air in something.
I guess that's the one
that's called one really.
So we published a couple papers
on this at competitions in Nips.
And so, interesting story,
did you ever talk to Nips about this work?
And Jeffrey Ton was in the audience, and
then you know I came back to my seat,
I was sitting next to him and he said,
there's one bit of information in your
talk which is that,
if you do all the sensible things,
it actually works.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Then that showed the after deadline of
work went on to make history
because it became widely adopted.
These ideas became widely adopted for
reading cheques and-
>> Yeah,
the bigger value adopted within AT&T but
not very much outside.
And I think it's a little difficult for
me to really understand why, but
the simple factor [INAUDIBLE].
So this was back in the late 80s,
and there was no Internet.
We had email, we had FTP, but
there was no Internet, really.
No two labs were using the same
software or hardware platform, right?
Some people are at some workstations,
others had other machines,
some people were using PCs or whatever.
There was no such thing as Python or
MATLAB or anything like that, right?
People are writing their own code.
I had spent a year and
a half basically writing,
me and when he was still a student.
We're working together,
and we spent a year and
a half basically just writing
a neural net simulator.
And at the time because there
was no match-up with Python.
You had to kind of write
your own interpreter, right?
To kind of control it.
So we want our own list of interpreter.
And so all the networks written in
list using a numerical back hand.
Very similar to what we have now with
blocks that you can interconnect and
instead of many differentiation and
all that stuff that we;re familiar now,
with torsion by torsion,
tensile flow and all those things.
So then we developed
a bunch of applications.
We got together with a group of engineers.
Very smart people.
Some of them were like theoretical
physicists who kind of turned
engineer at the Bell Labs.
Chris Dodgers was one
of them who then had to
distinguished career at
Microsoft research afterwards.
And Krieg Nolan.
But keep on and we're collaborating
with them to kind of make this
technology practical.
>> I see.
>> And so
together we developed this
characterization systems.
And that meant integrating,
convolutional net with things like,
similar to things like we now call
CRFs for interpreting sequences of
characters not just individual address.
>> Yeah,
right to the net paper had
partially under neural network and
partially under atomic machinery
>> Right, to pull it together?
>> Yeah, that's right.
And so the first half on the paper
is on convolutional nets, and
the paper is mostly cited for that.
And then the second half,
very few people have read it,
[LAUGH] and it's about sort of sequence
level, discriminative running, and
basically structure prediction
with that normalization.
So it's very similar to CRF, in fact.
>> Fascinating
>> You know with PTCRFS over the years.
So that was very successful,
except that the day we were
celebrating the deployment of
that system in major bank,
we worked with this group that I
was mentioning that was kind of
doing the engineering of the whole system.
And then another product group in
a different part of the country
that belonged to a subsidiary
of AT&T called NCR.
So this is the-
>> [CROSSTALK]
>> National Cash Register, right.
They also build large ATM machines, and
they build large check
reading machines for banks.
So they were the customers, if you want.
They were using our check billing systems.
And they had deployed it in a bank.
I can't remember which bank it was.
They deployed those, so
there were ATM machines in a French book.
So they could read the check you
would deposit, and we were all at
a fancy restaurant celebrating
the department of this thing where,
when the company announced that
it was breaking itself up.
So this was 1995 and
AT&T announced that it was breaking
itself up into two companies.
So there was AT&T, and then there
was Lucen Technologies, and NCR.
So NCR was spun off, and
Lucent Technologies was spun off.
And the engineering group went with Lucent
Technologies, and the product group,
of course, went with NCR.
And the sad thing is that the AT&T
lawyers in their infinite wisdom
assigned the patents,
there was a patent on covolutional net
which is thankfully expired.
>> I see [LAUGH].
>> [LAUGH] Expired in 2007.
About ten years ago.
And they signed patent to NCR, but
there was nobody in NCR who actually
knew even what a convolutional
net was really.
And so the patent was in the hands of
people who had no idea what they had.
And we were in a different company
that now could not really develop
the technology, and our engineering
team was in a separate company,
because we went with AT&T and
engineering went with Lucent, and
the product group went with NCR.
So it was a little depressing [LAUGH].
>> So in addition to your early work,
when your networks were Part,
you kept persisting on neural networks
even when there was some sort
of winter for neural net.
So what was like that?
>> Well, so I persisted and
didn't persist in some ways.
I was always convinced that eventually
those techniques would come back to
the fore, and sort of people would figure
out how to use them in practice, and
it would be useful.
So I always had that in
the back of my mind.
But in 1996,
when AT&T broke itself up, and
all of our work on character recognition,
basically,
was kind of broken up because the part
of the group went in separate way,
I was also promoted to department head,
and I had to figure out what to work on.
And this was the early days of
the Internet, we're talking 1995.
And I had the idea somehow
that one big problem about
the emergence of the Internet
was going to be to bring
all the knowledge that we had
on paper to the digital world.
And so I started, actually,
a project called DjVu, D-J-V-U,
which was to compress scanned documents,
essentially,
so they could be distributed
over the Internet.
And this project was really fun for a
while, and had some success, although AT&T
really didn't know what to do with it.
>> Yeah, I remember that, really helping
dissemination of online research papers.
>> Yeah, that's right, exactly.
And we scanned the entire proceedings of
NIPS, and we made them available online-
>> I see, I remember that.
>> To kind of demonstrate how that worked.
And we could compress high resolution
pages to just a few kilobytes.
>> So ConvNet,
starting from some of your much
earlier work has now come and
pretty much taken over the field
of computer vision, and
starting to encroach significantly
into even other fields.
So just tell me about how
you saw that whole process.
>> [LAUGH] So
to tell you how I thought this
was going to happen early on.
So first of all, I always believed
that this was going to work.
It required fast computers and lots of
data, but I always believed, somehow,
that this was going to be
the right thing to do.
What I thought, originally, when I was at
Bell Labs, that there was going to be some
sort of continuous progress along these
directions as machines got more powerful.
And we were even designing chips to run
convolutional nets at Bell Labs, but
now those are actually in hospital graph
separately had two different chips for
running convolutional
nets really efficiently.
And so we thought there was going to
be a kind of a pick up of this, and
kind of growing interest and
sort of continuous progress for it.
But in fact, because of the sort
of interest for neural nets,
sort of dying in the mid-90s,
that didn't happen.
So there was kind of a dark period of six
or seven years between 1995 roughly and
2002 when basically nobody
was working on this.
In fact, there was a little bit of work.
There was some work at Microsoft
in the early 2000s on using
convolutional nets for
Chinese character recognition.
>> Group, yeah, exactly.
And there was some other small work for
face detection and
things like this in France, and in various
other places, but it was very small.
I discovered actually recently
that a couple groups that came
up with ideas that are essentially very
similar to convolutional nets, but
never quite published it the same way for
medical image analysis.
And those were mostly in
the context of commercial systems.
And so
it never quite made it to the population.
I mean, it was after our first work
on convolutional nets, and they were
not really aware of it, but it sort of
developed in parallel a little bit.
So several people got kind of similar
ideas several years interval.
But then I was really
surprised by how fast
interest picked up after the ImageNet-
>> 2012
>> In 2012, so it's the end of 2012.
It was kind of a very
interesting event at ECCV,
in Florence,
where there was a workshop on ImageNet.
And they already knew that
had won by a large margin.
And so everybody was waiting for talk.
And most people in the computer vision
community had no idea what a convolutional
net was.
I mean, they heard me talk about it.
I actually had an invited talk at
CVPR in 2000 where I talked about it,
but most people had not
paid much attention to it.
Senior people did,
they knew what it was, but
the more junior people in the community
were really, had no idea what it was.
And so just gives his talk, and he doesn't
explain what a convolutional net is
because he assumes everybody knows, right?
because he comes from a so he says,
here's how everything is connected,
and how we transform the data and
what results we get.
Again, assuming that
everybody knows what it is.
And a lot of people
are incredibly surprised.
And you could see the opinion of people
changing as he was kind of giving
his talk, very senior people in the field.
>> So you think that workshop was
a defining moment that swayed a lot
of the computer vision community.
>> Yeah, definitely.
>> That's right, yeah.
>> That's the way it happened, yeah,
right there.
>> So today, you retain a faculty position
at NYU, and you also lead FAIR,
Facebook AI Research.
I know you have a pretty unique point of
view on how corporate research should
be done.
Do you want to share
your thoughts on that?
>> Yeah, so I mean, one of the beautiful
things that I managed to do at Facebook in
the last four years is that I was given
a lot of freedom to setup FAIR the way
I thought was the most appropriate,
because this was the first research
organization within Facebook.
Facebook is a sort of
engineering-centric company.
And so far was really focused on sort
of survival or short-term things.
And Facebook was about to turn ten
years old, had a successful IPO.
And was basically thinking about
the next ten years, right?
I mean, Mark Zuckerberg was thinking,
what is going to be important for
the next ten years?
And the survival of the company
was not in question anymore.
So this is the kind of transition where
a large company can start to think, or
it was not such a large
company at the time.
Facebook had 5,000 employees or
so, but it had the luxury to
think about the next ten years and
what would be important in technology.
And Mark and his team decided
that AI was going to be a crucial
piece of technology for connecting people,
which is the mission of Facebook.
And so they explored several ways
to kind of build an effort in AI.
They had a small internal group,
engineering group,
experimenting with convolutional nets and
stuff that were getting really good
results in face recognition and various
other things, which peaked their interest.
And they explored the idea of hiring
a bunch of young researchers, or
acquiring a company, or things like this.
And they settled on the idea of hiring
someone senior in the field, and
then kind of setting up
a research organization.
And it was a bit of a culture shock,
initially, because
the way research operates in the company
is very different from engineering, right?
You have longer time scales and horizon.
And researchers tend to be very
conservative about the choice of places
where they want to work.
And I made it very clear very early
on that research needs to be open,
that researchers need to not only
be encouraged to publish, but
be even mandated to publish.
And also be evaluated on
criteria that are similar to
what we used to evaluate
academic researchers.
[COUGH] And so what Mark and
Mike Schroepfer, the CTO of the company,
who is my boss now, said, they said,
Facebook is a very open company.
We distribute a lot of
stuff in open source.
Schroepfer, the CTO,
comes from the open source world.
>> Mozilla.
>> He was from Mozilla before that,
and a lot of people came from that world.
So that was in the DNA of the company,
so that made me
very confident that we could kind of
set up an open research organization.
And then the fact that the company is not
obsessively compulsive about IP as some
other companies are makes it much easier
to collaborate with universities and
have arrangements by which a person
can have a foot in industry and
a foot in academia.
>> And you find that valuable,
yourself?
>> Absolutely, yes.
Yeah, so if you look at my
publications over the last four years,
the vast majority of them
are publications with my students at
NYU.
>> I see.
>> Because at Facebook,
I did a lot of organizing the lab, hiring,
set the direction and advising,
and things like this.
But I don't get involved in individual
research projects to get my name on
papers.
And I don't care to get my name
on papers anymore, but it's-
>> It's not sending out someone else to do
your dirty work rather than doing
all the dirty work yourself.
>> Exactly, and you never want to put
yourself, you want to
stay behind the scene.
You don't want to put yourself in
competition with people in your lab in
that case.
>> I'm sure you get asked this a lot but
hoping you answer for all the people
watching this video as well.
What advice do you have for
someone wanting to get involved in the,
break into AI?
>> [LAUGH] I mean,
it's such a different world now than
when it was when I got started.
But I think what's great now is it's very
easy for people to get involved at some
level, the tools that are available are so
easy to use now, in terms of whatever.
You can have a run through on the cheap
computer in your bedroom, [LAUGH] and
basically train your conventional net or
your current net to do whatever,
and there's a lot of tools.
You can learn a lot from online material
about this without, it's not very onerous.
So you see high school students
now playing with this right?
Which is kind of great, I think and
they certainly are growing interest
from the student population to learn
about machine learning and AI and
it's very exciting for young people and
I find that wonderful I think.
So my advice is, if you want to get
into this, make yourself useful.
So make a contribution to an open
source project, for example.
Or make an implementation of some standard
algorithm that you can't find the code of
online, but you'd like to make
it available to other people.
So take a paper that
you think is important,
and then re-implement the algorithm,
and then put it open source package,
or contribute to one of
those open source packages.
And if the stuff you write is interesting
and useful, you'll get noticed.
Maybe you'll get a nice job at
a company you really wanted a job at,
or maybe you'll get accepted in your
favorite PhD program or things like this.
So I think that's a good way to get
started.
>> So
open source contributions is a good way to
enter the community, give back to learn.
>> Yeah, that's right,
that's right.
>> Thanks a lot Jan that was fascinating,
I've known you for many years and
it's still fascinating to hear all these
details of all the stories that
have gone in over the years.
>> Yeah, there's many stories like this
that, reflecting back at the moment
when they happen you don't realize,
what importance it might take 10 or
20 years later.
>> Yeah, thank you.
>> Thanks.