In this section, we're going to take
a look at some DL4J example code.
Simple example builds a neural net,
processes a small data set to make
predictions of the species of
an iris based upon its measurements.
The code's available here.
The data file's also available there,
and there's direct links to the code.
You could also just clone the whole repo,
and
that repo also contains any other DL4J
exercises that we've done in this course.
The data looks like this, and
the first four fields are measurements.
The last field is the class.
Species 0 might be iris setosas,
species 1 would be iris virginica,
species 2 would be iris versicolor.
So three species of irises, and then
the four measures are their sepal length,
sepal width, petal length,
and petal width.
So the first four fields are features.
They will be ingested using the DataVec
tools such as CSV RecordReader.
And they will become an INDArray,
an indexed n-dimensional array.
Last field is the label.
It will also become an INDArray and
it will get passed to the neural net.
The neural net will make its
prediction based upon the features and
then will compare it to the known label.
So we're performing
supervised training here.
So the steps that we're going to
need to perform in our code,
we're going to need to read the file.
We're going to need to parse the lines.
We're going to need to specify
which field is the label, and
which field are the features or
the measurements.
We're going to have to
create a DataSet object,
a collection of INDArrays to
pass into our neural net.
INDArrays are sometimes called tensors and
then build a neural net and train it.
We're going to be using a RecordReader.
And here's the JavaDoc for
the RecordReader and the Java Doc for
the CSV RecordReader.
Note that the second URL I had to split
on the line because it was too long to
feed into the slide, so
that's all one string.
And then we're going to be using
a RecordReaderDataSetIterator to build
the dataset, the INDArray of the features
and the INDArray of the labels.
Main documentation for
DeepLearning4J is available, Here.
The JavaDoc for DataVec is available here.
And the JavaDoc for
DeepLearning4J is available there.
So step one, we need to write
some code to read the data file.
The data file has no header,
it's all data.
So we specify that we don't
need to skip any lines.
The data is comma delimited so we specify
that we'll be using a delimiter of comma.
And then we build our RecordReader, so
we're going to create a new instance of
the CSVRecordReader, and we're
going to pass it those two parameters,
the number of lines to skip and the
delimiter, so that will be zero and comma.
We pass the RecordReader our file path.
So we just point it to
iris.txt to read the file.
So we pass it a FileSplit,
the file, iris.txt.
We set some parameters for
the data set iterator.
We specify that there's three classes.
We specify that the last field,
the fifth field starting at zero,
so the label index is four,
that's right here.
So we specify that
the label index is four.
We specify that there's three classes.
And we specify that we're going
to read 150 lines per batch.
There's only 150 lines in this data file,
so
we're going to be reading it all and
processing it as a single batch.
So what the RecordReader does it returns
an iterator over a List of Writables.
And what is a Writable?
A Writable's an efficient
serialization method.
The neural net requires a tensor or
an INDArray
of numeric values, and the
RecordReaderDataSetIterator gives us that.
So it converts the RecordReader's list of
Writables into that tensor, that INDArray.
And then once we have it into an INDArray,
we'll have one for the features and
one for the labels.
The features will get
passed through the network.
The network will make its predictions, and
then we'll compare it to the known labels.
And so there's the code for
that operation.
A neural net performs best
if the data is shuffled.
In the case of this data file, it is not.
So we're going to shuffle it after
we have loaded it into a data set.
You could also shuffle the data at just
about any point along the ingestion path.
Splitting the data between test and
train, so
we're going to train on 65% of the data.
That code is right here,
and then we're going to
validate the outcome of the train
neural net with the test data.
We're going to normalize the data set, so
you'll see measurements like 4 and 1.5.
But we're going to normalize and
standardize those so
that the max value is 1 and
the min value is 0.
In order to do that, we're going to
need to call normalizer.fit.
Normalizer.fit will step
through the data once,
find the observed min and
the observed max.
And then we can apply that in this
second step here to our data set
to convert the values to values
between a range of zero and one.
And of course,
we also need to normalize the test data.
Then we need to build a neural net.
So here where it's specifying some
parameters, we're setting a seed.
So we set a consistent random seed so
that we can run multiple times and
have consistent results.
The first step of building a neural net is
random initialization of the weights, and
we would like repeatable results.
So we set a seed so we get the same
random initialization of the weights.
Specify the number of iterations.
That's how many times we're going to
back propagate, or update our weights.
Specify some other parameters such
as the activation function for
the hidden layer and
the wait initialization algorithm.
And those are kind of standard, at least
the Javier weight initialization is.
We set the learning rate to 0.1,
enable regularization and
then we add some layers.
So we've got a input layer,
we've got a hidden layer and
then we have our output layer.
Input layer is determined
by the number of features.
Output layer is determined
by the number of classes.
And then we chose how many nodes
to have in the hidden layer.
Not too many parameters to work with here.
The neural net isn't
necessarily going to need
too many parameters to solve this problem.
So we then need to run the neural
net on the training data.
So we take our configuration.
Note in the previous file we're building
a configuration, as you see here.
And then we take that configuration
in the next section of code and
we build a model from it, right there.
We initialize the model.
I set some listeners so
we get some output of progress.
The listeners are going to
show us the score, what
the value of the lost function is, how
well the neural net's doing, basically.
When the neural net is done training,
then we evaluate it.
You could also evaluate it, perhaps,
every few steps to see how it's
performing as you move along.
The loss function will give you some
idea of it, that's on the training data.
It's useful to evaluate on some test data
that the neural net has not trained on.
So we build an evaluation class,
we pass the trained model our test data,
and then we see how well it did
on data that it did not train on.
And that's it.
So there's a complete example of the code
available at that GitHub repo
that we saw in the first slide.
And that's a very simple
straightforward DL4J example.
In the next section,
I'll be showing you how to classify time
series data using a recurrent
neural net along short-term memory.
Recurrent neural net, and then there
will also be a section that looks at
multivariate time series data as well.
So the first example is univariate,
the second example is multivariate.
Thank you.