So this lecture is about creating
an anomaly detector using neural networks.
You want to do this in
an unsupervised manner.
So remember, in supervised learning,
we have our data, but each item in your
data set needs to be assigned to a label,
either class or continuous value.
We call this target which
we want to predict.
In the case of anomaly detection,
this can be a binary target
indicating an anomaly or not.
Or a continuous value, so
an anomaly score or RUL score.
RUL stands for remaining useful lifetime.
Given that labeled data,
a model is trained.
In this case, a supervised one
because we tell the model to replicate
the underlying hidden function using
the supervised label data set.
There are more unlabeled than
labeled data sets available.
Therefore, we want to
get rid of the bus but
it turns out this is not a trivial task.
So look at this time series for example.
It is an accelerometer based vibration
data set which is attached to peering,
one vibration axis is shown in red and
one is shown in blue.
So how can we predict if the peering
is in a broken or healthy condition.
In this case, I'm telling you
that the peering is totally fine.
So let's have a look at a data
set from the faulty peering.
Hm, hard to tell isn't it?
So let's zoom in a bit and check again.
So in the top we see half the data, and
at the bottom we see the faulty one.
At least we can tell
that they are different.
So we are using our biological neural
network in our brain in order to see this.
So what if an artificial neural
network can do the same.
So if our brain looks at two
different time-series plots,
it's able to spot the difference.
In theory, we can implement the artificial
neural network to do exactly the same.
A convolution neural network, for
example, can look at the two plots and
tell whether they are different or not.
To be honest, I haven't tried this,
so maybe that's an exercise for you.
But what we can do is, using the LSTM,
a long short term memory network,
for time series analysis.
Remember that the LSTM
is still incomplete, and
ideally fits time series and
sequence data.
But isn't there a problem?
Since this is unsupervised machine
learning, we don't have labels available.
So the task of a neural
network is to take X and
adjust the ways that it reconstructs Y,
but we don't have Y.
So hopefully,
you remember what the outer encoder does.
So an outer encoder is using X
as input and output as well.
So an outer encoder will try to
reconstruct what it sees on the left-hand
side on the right-hand side.
And if you now train the outer encoder,
with an LSTM and healthy data,
it tries to reconstruct the healthy data.
And remember that it runs
through a neural bottleneck.
And once it's trained,
it will have a hard time to reconstruct
faulty data, that's the point.
That's how the anomaly detector works.
But how do we know if you're
currently showing healthy or
faulty data to the model.
So this is quite simple.
Because in a real world scenario,
there is much more healthy data,
than broken one available for training.
So if you randomly pick a sample, the
chances are very high that it is healthy
data, and the chance is of course very
low, that we've picked faulty data.
There are much more sophisticated
strategies behind that,
which are often domain specific, therefore
we won't dive more into details here.
In the next module,
we will implement an LSTM outer encoder
based anomaly detector using keras.
So stay tuned.