In this module,
we will use our LSTM anomaly detector, and
turn it into a real time
anomaly detection system.
So if you want to get an anomaly detection
system from a playground into production,
you have to hook it up to data source.
Either we can directly access data
from a data source for training, or
we need to run from process in between.
One special case which is the most
interesting one in my opinion
is looking on a realtime data stream.
Because a lot of data loses it's
value within the first seconds.
So think of a stock market taker or
cryptcurrency market ticker or
ask data or IoT sense data.
We can data into creation is most of
them with some sort od message cue or
stream engine.
At the lowest level, even a TCP connection
can be seen as a message queue.
Although, if you can't consume
your messages fast enough,
you will lose data due to time outs.
Even the UDP connection can be seen
as some kind of a message queue.
But your messages can get lost and
order is not preserved.
Often also, HTTP with rest, our web
circuits are used as message queues.
MQTT is often used for IoT telemetry use
cases because it's very lightweight.
MQTT defines the message protocol,
so it decouples on the end receiver.
We will use MQTT in our example.
Kafka is also an example of a message
protocol which is widely used for
all sorts of data.
At the other end of the spectrum
resides streaming engines,
like IBM Streams,
Apache Spark, or Apache Flink,
which do not only allow data movement but
also data transformation in between.
So in our case,
we use the MQTT message program, which is
provided by the IBM Watson IoT platform.
Realtime SLR metadata is sometimes have
to get for demonstration purposes,
that's why we use the simulator
implemented on top of Node-RED.
For the queue and
consume it directly from the deep learning
framework is fine for development.
But for production scenario,
we have to deploy a model.
A convenient way for this is using the
IBM Watson machine learning service which
supports various MLNT frameworks like
Spark ML, TensorFlow, PyTorch, and so on.
The cool thing is that
everything comes as a service so
you are not wasting your
time with operations.
So let's see how this is done
in real life, so stay tuned.