In this video,
I will explain how to use SystemML.
SystemML provides a R-like language
called Declarative Machine Learning,
or DML, for data scientists to
implement machine learning algorithm.
Here is a sample of DML script.
In this script, we generate a random
matrix X, with 1,000 cols and
sparsity 0.5.
The number of rows is provided by
the user using the dollar parameter nr.
We then multiply the matrix X with
the transpose and compute the sum.
It is important to note that DML
simply simplifies the development and
deployment of the machine
learning algorithms.
It does so,
by separating algorithm semantics from
the underlying data representation and
runtime execution plan.
DML is expressive enough to cover
a broad class of algorithms.
Such as Descriptive Statistics,
Classification, Clustering,
Regression, Matrix Factorization,
Dimensionality Reduction,
Survival Model, and Deep Learning.
These algorithms are pre-packaged with
SystemML and available on GitHub.
SystemML also supports commonly used data
transformation task such as recording,
demicording, bending, scaling,
and missing values imputation.
SystemML has a cost less compiler
that automatically generates
hybrid runtime execution plans.
That are composed of single node and
distributed operations.
These plans are generated depending
on data and cluster characteristics,
such as data size, data sparsity,
cluster size and memory configuration.
In our previous example,
if the user specifies a small linear,
then SystemML might compile
a single node plan.
On the other hand,
if linear is large, then SystemML
might compile Hadoop or a Spark plan.
The language component
passes the DML script into a hierarchy
of statement blocks and statements.
It also performs syntactic analysis,
live variable analysis, and
semantic validation.
We then construct a directed cyclic
graph of high-level operators,
called as HOPs, per statement.
SystemML optimizer performs various
optimizations on this HOP DAGs.
For example,
algebraic simplifications rewrite,
interprocedural analysis, and
matrix multiplication chain optimization.
Each HOP DAG is compiled into a dug up
low level operators called a slopes,
based on memory estimation,
data and cluster characteristics.
Loops are back in specific operator and
have corresponding real-time
implementation called instructions.
SystemML runs in an embeddable,
standalone, and in cluster mode.
It also supports various APIs in Scala,
Python, and Java.