In this video,
I will explain how to use SystemML.
We'll walk through full example
program that will explain
how to write a DMS script and
use SystemML's Python API.
First, we'll understand
how to implement a simple,
Hello World and
matrix multiplication example using DML.
The goal of this example
is to understand how to
write a simple DML script and
use ML Context API.
Then we'll move on to a more complicated
example where we will understand how
to implement three different algorithms
to train a linear aggression model.
The goal here is to understand how
System ML enables data scientist
to implement that custom algorithm,
using for this specific uses.
The example, three and four explains,
how a data scientist who
prefers to invoke a pre-implemented
algorithm, can use SystemML.
Finally, we understand how to
drain a simple neural network,
using kiosk to DML API.
You can install SystemML using PIP.
Since I've already installed SystemML,
I will skip this step.
Instead I will check the version SystemML
previously installed on this system.
It shows that I have installed SystemML
1.1, which is currently under development.
SystemML version 1.1 requires park two and
above.
If you are using a different kernel, you
can change the kernel using this option.
In this cell,
we import MLContext class and DML method.
From this system a mini package
we create an American text object
by passing either a spark context or
a spark session object.
Next, we check the version of SystemML
using American text information.
In the next cell, we create a simple d.
We create a simple DML script,
that brings hello word.
Notice DML script object is created
by passing the DMS strength,
to the DML material
being reported earlier.
We then execute the script.
Using American text, execute matter.
Let's say that instead of using system
mms building script print method.
We want to use Python's print method.
In this case, we create a string in DML.
And specify that we want to
fetch that string as an output.
Then we use American text
get method after execution.
Let's load numpy and
sklearn which we'll use in later examples.
Now that we know how to
execute a DMS script and
fetch the output using ML context,
let's understand how
to pass input to SystemML
using ML context input method.
Four, we can yield a random matrix X
with a thousand columns and sparsity .5.
The number of throughs are passed by the
user by the dollar parameter [INAUDIBLE].
We then multiply the matrix X with
the transpose in computer sum.
The pass the value of the dollar parameter
enough, in this case, 1e raised to six.
Using the input method, we now execute
the script using American text.
As you can see, it spawned a spark job
likely to generate a random matrix.
When this job is finished,
the value of s will be greater.
Which is [INAUDIBLE].