So, let's have a look at the IBM Watson Natural Language Classifier.
So, this is a natural language processing service.
It's just based on deep learning and comes as a service in the cloud,
and again it's just the ReST API,
and we are seeing here a little demo user interface.
So, this is an already pre-trained classifier.
Of course, you can train the classifier on your own with your own data,
but this has been trained with weather-related data.
Let's ask a question,
and you see here the classifier is 100% confident that we are talking about temperature.
So, I assume the question,
"Should I prepare for sleet?"
will recite a condition, let's see.
Let's see here, you have 0.94% accuracy that we are talking about conditions.
So, this is just a little example.
So, you can train this classifier in the cloud using ReST API,
you don't care about the topology and parameterization of your neural network.
And it basically just works.
Okay? Let's see what we can do more, and