Let's get started with
Deep Feedforward Networks.
So this is an example of hypothetical
sensor data of a production machine.
So each row contains information about
a production of a particular part with
an associated part number.
So our goal is to predict asperity
which is highly correlated with effect
if the part is healthy or faulty
based on the observed sensor values.
So which column can be used to
create a simple rule for this?
First we have to observe that all
three columns are aggregations
of some sort of sensor value.
So we are losing information.
But this is fine for this example.
We notice that the vibration aggregation
gives us the best indication for our rule,
so let's code it.
So let's start with
creation of a data point.
The first field is part number,
so let's take 100.
The next field is next temp,
which will be set to 35.
The middle temp is 35 as well.
And finally set the max vibration to 12.
After producing the part, asperity
is measured, so we set it to 0.32.
So let's copy this four times to
reflect our four measurements.
As in the example of the slides, I will
update those values now accordingly.
Let's implement our simple rule to
predict asperity based on a sensor value.
Obviously, max vibration has
the largest impact on the outcome.
Therefore, if max vibration is greater
than 100, we return 13 or 0.33 otherwise.
If we now test this function,
we get quite good results.
So now let's see if we can do
better without hard coding a rule.
This formula here is called
a linear regression model.
It's called regression because it
predicts a continuous value based
on observations x and weights w.
Let's create our first machine
learning algorithm called linear
regression in Python.
So remember that we have to create
a linear combination between our input
fields and some parameters w.
And if you plot this,
w1 is the offset of the line.
So if you run this now,
you obviously run into an error
because we haven't defined w yet.
So let's do this now.
And now let's choose the parameters
w in a way that it somehow resembles
the rule which we have created before.
If you set everything to 0,
you get 0 as a result.
So let's try to adjust those values.
We cheat a bit, we just take
the numbers of our dataset and
play around until we get a better result.
As we can see,
we are getting relatively close here.
In a real world scenario, of course,
those parameters w will be set by
an optimizer which is part of neural
network or machine learning training.
Maybe if you noticed that there is one
x missing in order to get equally sized
vectors.
Therefore, we define x0 as 1.
This is the bias term, or
the offset of the linear regression.
So now we can multiply x with w,
because both vectors have the same length.
If we just write down what we've learned
before, we'll come up with the following.
Well, doesn't look this
like linear regression?
Just put y at the end and you can see it.
So that's cool.
We can express linear regression with
a single vector-vector multiplication.
It turns out that parts with an asperity
greater than 1 are not usable, so
we consider them to be faulty or broken.
Let's change our table to reflect this.
Let's code it.
So let's change this regression data set
into a binary classification data set.
Then our rule gets more simpler and
also more precise.
And in addition,
it's changed our linear regression
model to a logistic regression one.
In order to achieve this, just add
a sigmoid computation step to our website.
So the neural side is between 0 and 1, and
by selecting a threshold in the middle, so
we can basically turn this model
into binary classification model.
So this looks brilliant already.
So the logistic sigmoid function
squashes a range from minus
infinity to plus infinity
to a range between 0 and 1.
So this means we can easily turn our
lineal regression model into a logistic
regression model and
create a binary classifier.
Let's wait, you have to define
a threshold between 0 and
1 in order to get the binary classifier,
in order to get a clear separation between
the classes instead of a continuous range.
So why am I telling you all about
this in a neural networks class?
So let's have a look at the most simple
neural network, the so called perceptron.
The idea is that your input vectors get
multiplied with the weights vector and
finally the sum is taken.
Note that even the biased
term is taken into the sum.
So what you should be aware of is
that this is nothing else than
a linear combination or dot product
between two vectors, or in other words,
linear regression.
If you replace thick mode from the
logistic regression function with a simple
step function, you're done and
you have created a Perceptron.
A perceptron is a binary
linear classifier.
So now let's see how we can improve this.
By the way, the first perceptron has been
implemented on top of an IBM 704 in 1954,
which was the first computer with
floating point arithmetic hardware.
So this guy here is a feedforward neural
network with a so called hidden layer.
In order to understand this better,
let's code it first.
So Python dictionaries are of course
not the best way to do data science.
Let's convert our data points to a matrix.
First, we have to get rid of the labels
which are called keys in Python
dictionaries, And
turn each data point into an array.
Neither asperity nor part number are
required here, so let's get rid of those.
But we have to align this array or
vector, the size of the weight vector.
So we have to add a 1 at the beginning
in order to support the bias.
So this is what we want.
Native Python arrays are slow and
also not supporting linear
algebra operations.
So let's work this into a NumPy array.
And let's do it for all the data points.
Let's create a function called neuron,
which computes the logistic function for
just one data point.
We define a weight vector w,
Which we initialize randomly.
And use the dot product between
the data point and the weight vector,
In order to compute the linear
regression function.
Then we apply sigmoid as activation
function and we're done.
So let's see if this compiles and runs.
Note that we don't get anything
useful here because we
randomly initialized the weight
vector w and didn't train it.
By the way,
training means updating the weight vector.
So now let's pimp this function
a bit in order to compute all data
points in parallel.
First, we have to improve the sigmoid
function that it also takes multiple
values at once.
Fortunately, NumPy does the job for
us here.
Since this function now takes a matrix,
we also have to change our weights
from vector to matrix as well.
And finally we have to create
a matrix from our input data.
We can use NumPy again because a nested
array is nothing else than a matrix.
So now we can compute one layer in one go.
Now let's create a second layer.
We only have to change the weight matrix
because the second layer is computed
independently from the first layer.
And as a last step, we just stick those
two computations on top of each other and
we're done with our first
feedforward neural network.
Of course, the predicted values
are incorrect because we're using
randomly initialized weight matrices.
This is now an untrained
feedforward neural network.
Note that a single hidden layer on your
network is capable of representing any
mathematical function.
This is known as the universal
function approximation theory.
So you might ask yourself why
are multiple hidden layer or
other topologies used at all.
This is because of training.
Even if you can represent
any mathematical function,
you might not be able to train it.
Because training means
selecting good values for
the weight matrices, and
this is not an easy task.
But let's talk about this later.
Let's get started with
Recurrent Neural Networks.