In this video,
we're going to talk about more general,
non-sequential models in Keras
using the functional API.
So there is two types of models in Keras.
We've seen the sequential already.
There is another type called model,
which you would use if you were
in need of non-sequential models.
Once defined, and we will see
how to do that in just a second.
The model can be trained and
evaluated exactly like sequential models.
So you don't have to learn
anything about that part.
Using the functional API,
you would usually start with model and
configuring one or several inputs.
Once you have those inputs defined,
we define transformations for
those inputs, until you arrive at one or
several outputs.
So let's look at an example.
This is an example we kind of have
already seen using the sequential model.
Mainly we do predictions of
100 predictions using amnest.
We've got two layers here first.
First one is Dense time layers
which we have already seen and
the second one is a new
layer type called Input.
On top of that,
we import our new model class.
As before, we define the number of classes
as 10 because we have 10 digits here.
And we define an input layer of shape 784,
which is of vector shape length 784.
Then what we do next is new,
we define a Dense of output dimension 512,
but instead of simply defining it,
we call it on our inputs.
So we define x as a Dense
layer applied to our inputs.
So what that means is, every layer
in Keras, actually, every model for
that purpose can be called in tensors
to output tensors, and we do that here.
So this is part of the functional API.
We can do this step again and
apply our intermediary x to a Dense
layer again to arrive at yet another x.
Finally, we can do this a third time,
this time with the number of classes
as output dimension to
arrive at our predictions.
So this procedure of calling
layers on different inputs,
you can do that in any fashion, and
slowly build up very complicated models.
Now, to initialize and
run a model is quite simple,
you simply specify the inputs and
the outputs, that's it.
Compilation step, fitting, evaluating and
so on, it's just the same thing as before.