in the last video you saw what a single
hidden layer neural network looks like
in this video let's go through the
details of exactly how this neural
network computers outputs what you see
is that is like logistic regression the
repeater of all the times let's take a
look so this is what's a two layer
neural network
let's go more deeply into exactly what
this neural network
compute now was said before that
logistic regression the circle images
the regression really represents two
steps of computation first you compute Z
as follows and in second you compute the
activation as a sigmoid function of Z so
a neural network just does this a lot
more times let's start by focusing on
just one of the nodes in the hidden
there and this look at the first node in
the hidden layer so I've grayed out the
other nodes for now so similar to
logistic regression on the left this
node in a hidden layer does two steps of
computation right the first step and
think it's as the left half of this node
it computes Z equals W transpose X plus
B and the notation we'll use is um these
are all quantities associated with the
first hidden layer so that's why we have
a bunch of square brackets there and
this is the first node in the hidden
layer so that's why we have the
subscript one over there so first it
does that and then a second step is it
computes a 1 1 equals sigmoid of z11
like so so for both Z and ay the
notational convention is that a Li the L
here in superscript square brackets
refers to layer number and the I
subscript here refers to the nodes in
that layer so then they will be looking
at is layer 1 that is a hidden layer
node 1 so that's why the superscript and
subscript were on both 1 1 so that
little circle that first node in your
network represents carrying out these
two steps of computation now let's look
at the second node in your network the
second node in the hidden layer of in
your network similar to the logistic
regression unit on the left this little
circle represents two steps of
computation the first step is a
confusing Z this is still layer 1
pronounced the second node equals W
transpose X plus V
- and then a 1/2 equals Sigma z12 and
again feel free to pause the video if
you want but you can double check that
the superscript and subscript notation
is consistent with what we have written
here above in purple so we'll talk
through the first two hidden units in
the neural network on hidden units three
and four also represents some
computations so now let me take this
pair of equations and this pair of
equations and let's copy them to the
moon fly so here's our network and
here's the first and there's a second
equations they were worked on previously
for the first and the second hidden
units if you then go through and write
out the corresponding equations for the
third and fourth hidden units you get
the following and those make sure this
notation is clear this is the vector W 1
1 this is a vector transpose x I think
so that's what the superscript G there
represents this is a vector transpose
now as you might have guessed if you're
actually implementing in your network
doing this with a for loop seems really
inefficient so what we're going to do is
take these four equations and vectorize
so I'm going to start by showing how to
compute Z as a vector it turns out you
could do it as follows
let me take these WS and stack them into
a matrix then you have W 1 1 transpose
so that's a row vector of the column
vector transpose gives you a row vector
then W 1 2 transpose W 1 3 transpose of
V 1 4 transpose and so this by stacking
goes from for W vectors together you end
up with a matrix so another way to think
of this is that we have for logistic
regression unions there and each of the
logistic regression unions have a
corresponding parameter vector W and by
stacking those four vectors together you
end up with this four by three matrix so
if you then take this matrix and
multiply it by your input features x1 x2
x3 you end up with by our matrix
multiplication works you end up with w1
1 transpose x w1 w2 1 transpose X of U 3
1 transyl
XW 1 transpose X and then let's not
forget the bees so we now add to this a
vector
b11 b12 b13 in 1/4 so that they see this
then this is b11 b12 b13 e 1/4 and so
you see that each of the four rows of
this outcome correspond exactly to each
of these four rows of each these four
quantities that we had above so in other
words we've just shown that this thing
is therefore equal to V 1 1 V 1 to V 1 V
V 1 4 right as defined here and maybe
not surprisingly we're going to call
this whole thing the vector V 1 which is
taken by stacking up these um
individuals of these into a column
vector when we're vectorizing one of the
rules of thumb that might help you
navigate this is that when we have
different nodes in a layer or stack them
vertically so that's why when you have Z
1 1 2 Z 1 for those correspond to four
different nodes in the hidden layer and
so we stack these four numbers
vertically to form the vectors V 1 and
reduce one more piece of notation this 4
by 3 matrix here which we obtained by
stacking the lower case you know W 1 1 W
1 2 and so on we're going to call this
matrix W capital 1 and similarly this
vector or going to call B superscript 1
square bracket and so this is a 4 by 1
vector so now we've computed Z using
this vector matrix notation the last
thing we need to do is also compute
these values of a and so probably won't
surprise you to see that we're going to
define a 1 as just stacking together
those activation values a11 to a14 so
just take these 4 values and stack them
together in a vector called a1 and this
is going to be sigmoid of z1 where
there's no husband implementation of the
sigmoid function that takes in the four
elements of Z and applies the sigmoid
function element wise to it so just a
recap we figured out that z1 is equal to
W 1 times the vector X plus the vector B
1 and a 1
is sigmoid x z 1 let's just copy this to
the next slide and what we see is that
for the first layer of the neural
network given an input X we have that z1
is equal to w1 times X plus B 1 and a 1
is sick point of z1 and the dimensions
of this are 4 by 1 equals this is a 4 by
3 matrix times a 3 by 1 vector plus a 4
by 1 vector B and this is 4 by 1 same
dimensions and remember that we said X
is equal to a 0 right just like Y hat is
also equal to a 2 so if you want you can
actually take this X and replace it with
a 0 since a 0 is if you want as an alias
for the vector of input futures X now
through a similar derivation you can
figure out that the representation for
the next layer can also be written
similarly where what the output layer
does is it has associated with it so the
parameters W 2 and B 2 so W 2 in this
case is going to be a 1 by 4 matrix and
B 2 is just a real number as 1 by 1 and
so V 2 is going to be a real numbers
right as a 1 by 1 matrix is going to be
a 1 by 4 thing times a was 4 by 1 plus B
2 is 1 by 1 and so this gives you just a
real number and if you think of this
loss output unit as just being analogous
to logistic regression which had
parameters W and B on W really plays in
nablus role to W 2 transpose or W 2's
really W transpose and B is equal to B 2
right similar to you know cover up the
left of this network and ignore all that
for now then this is just this last
output unit there's a lot like logistic
regression except that instead of
writing the parameters as WMV we're
writing them as W 2 and B 2 with
dimensions one by four and one by one so
just a recap for logistic regression to
implement the output or the influence
prediction you compute Z equals W
transpose X plus B and a y hat equals a
equals sigmoid of z
when you have a new network who have one
fit in there what you need to implement
two computers output is just the four
equation and you can think of this as a
vectorized implementation of computing
the output of first these four
logistical russian units and hitting
there that's what this does and then
this which is regression in the output
layer which is what this does
I hope this description made sense but
takeaway is to compute the output of
this neural network all you need is
those four lines of code so now you've
seen how given a single input feature
vector at you can with four lines of
code compute the outputs of this viewer
Network um similar to what we did for
logistic regression will also want to
vectorize across multiple training
examples and we'll see that by stacking
up training examples in different colors
in the matrix or just slight
modification to this you also similar to
what you saw in which is regression be
able to compute the output of this
neural network not just on one example
at a time belong your say your
anti-trade set at a time so let's see
the details of that in the next video