all right I think that's be an exciting
video in this video you see how to
implement gradient descent for your
neural network with one hidden layer in
this video I'm going to just give you
the equations you need to implement in
order to get back propagation of the
gradient descent working and then in the
video after this one I'll give some more
intuition about why these particular
equations are the accurate equations or
the correct equations for computing the
gradients you need for your neural
network
so your neural network with a single
peasant layer for now will have
parameters W 1 V 1 W 2 and B 2 and so as
a reminder if you have NX alternative
the UM n 0 input features and N 1 hidden
units and n 2 output units in our
example so far don't yet n 2 equals 1
then the matrix W 1 will be N 1 by n 0 V
1 will be an N 1 dimensional vector so
you can write down as a 10-1 by 1
dimensional matrix really a column
vector the dimensions of W 2 will be n 2
by N 1 and the dimension of B 2 will be
n 2 by 1 right where again so far we've
only seen examples where n 2 is equal to
1 where you have just one a single
hidden unit so you also have a cost
function for a neural network and for
now I'm just going to assume that you're
doing binary classification so in that
case the cost of your parameters as
follows is going to be 1 over m of the
average of that loss function and so L
here is the loss when your new network
predicts y hat right this is really a a
2 when the ground should 0 is equal to Y
and if you're doing binary
classification the loss function can be
exactly what you use for logistic
earlier so to train the parameters your
algorithms you need to perform gradient
descent when training a neural network
is important to initialize the
parameters randomly rounded into all
zeros
we'll see later why that's the case but
after initializing the parameter to
something each loop of gradient descent
would compute the predictions
so you basically compute you know y hat
I for I equals 1 through m say and then
you need to compute the derivative so
you need to compute DW 1 and that's we
see the derivative of the cost function
with respect to the parameter W 1 you
need to compute another variable which
is going to call DP 1 which is the
derivative or the slope of your cost
function with respect to the variable B
1 and so on similarly for the other
parameters W 2 and B 2 and then finally
the gradient descent update would be to
update W 1 as W 1 minus alpha the
learning rate times d w1 v 1 gets
updated as B 1 minus the learning rate
times D B 1 as similarly for W 2 and B 2
and sometimes I use colon equals and
sometimes equals as either either the
notation works fine and so this would be
one iteration of gradient descent and
then your repeat this some number of
times until your parameters look like
they're converging so in previous videos
we talked about how to compute the
predictions how to compute the outputs
and we saw how to do that in a
vectorized way as well so the key is to
know how to compute these partial
derivative terms the DW 1 DB 1 as well
as the derivatives BW 2 and DP 2 so what
I'd like to do is just give you the
equations you need in order to compute
these derivatives and I'll defer to the
next video which is an optional video to
go great turn to Jeff about how we came
up with those formulas
so then just summarize again the
equations for for propagation so you
have Z 1 equals W 1 X plus B 1 and then
a 1 equals the activation function in
that layer applied other than Y since V
1 and then Z 2 equals W 2 A 1 plus B 2
and then finally difference all
vectorize across your training set right
a 2 is equal to G 2 of V 2 looking for
now if we assume you're doing binary
classification then this activation
function really should be the sigmoid
function so I'm just throw that in here
so that's the forward propagation or the
left-to-right forward computation for
your neural network next let's compute
the derivatives so this is the back
propagation step then it computes DZ 2
equals a 2 minus the ground truth Y and
just just as a reminder all this is
vectorize across example so the matrix Y
is this sum 1 by M matrix that lists all
of your M examples horizontally then it
turns out DW 2 is equal to this in fact
um these first three equations are very
similar to gradient descent for logistic
regression
X is equals 1 comma um keep DIMMs equals
true and just a little detail this NP
dot some is a Python numpy commands or
something across one dimension of a
matrix in this case summing horizontally
and what q DIMMs does is it prevents
- from outputting one of those funny
bank 1 various red where the dimensions
was you know n comma so by having keep
them sequels true this ensures that
Python outputs 4gb to a vector that is
sum and buy one technically this will be
I guess n to buy one in this case is
just a one by one number so maybe it
doesn't matter but later on we'll see
when it really matters so so far what
we've done is very similar to logistic
regression but now as you compute
continue to run back propagation you
would compute this Z 2 times G 1 prime
of Z 1 so this quantity G 1 prime is the
derivative of whatever was the
activation function you use for the
hidden layer and for the output layer I
assume that you're doing binary
classification with the sigmoid function
so that's already baked into that
formula for DZ 2 and this times is a
element-wise product so this year
there's going to be an N 1 by M matrix
and this here this element wise
derivative thing is also going to be an
N 1 by n matrix and so this times there
is another min wise product of two
matrices then finally DW 1 is equal to
that and DV 1 is equal to this and P dot
some D Z 1 X is equals 1 keep Tim's
equals true so whereas
previously the cheap business maybe
matter less if n2 is equal to 1000 sofa
one by one thing is there's a real
number here P p1 will be a n 1 by 1
vector and so you want Python you want n
P dot some output something of this
dimension rather than a family Matic one
array of that dimension which could end
up messing up some of your later
calculations the other way would be to
not have to keep them parameters but to
explicitly call in a reshape to reshape
the output of NP dot some into this
dimension which you would like DB so how
so that was for propagation in I guess
four equations and back propagation in I
guess six equations I know I just wrote
down these equations but in the next
optional video let's go over some
intuitions for how the six equations for
the back propagation algorithm were
derived please feel free to watch that
or not but either way if you implement
these algorithms you will have a correct
implementation of for profit backdrop
and you'll be able to compute the
derivatives you need in order to apply
gradient descent to learn the parameters
of your neural network it is possible to
implement design room and get it to work
without deeply understanding the
calculus a lot of successful people
earning practitioners do so but if you
want you can also watch the next video
just to get a bit more intuition about
the derivation of these of these
equations