So, one example of new network
already deployed for you in the cloud is IBM Watson Visual Recognition.
So this is a computer vision API,
and the cool thing here is you cannot only use it as it is,
you can train it with your own data.
Now, let's have a look how it performs.
So first of all, we take this example image here. This a Chihuahua.
You can see here, it's also recognized by the service.
Let's take another one. Okay. It's quite nice.
So that you know that I'm not cheating,
I am now using a photo of mine but let's actually create a new one.
So let's drag and drop this.
And you see here,
he got my age right and also my gender,
and it's a portrait photo in front of my green screen.
So that's basically the way how to use the service for scoring.
But now, we can train it with our own data.
And let's take some sample images which are already here,
but you can also upload your own database
or you can also use a REST API to interact with the service.
So this is only just a demo application.
So let's select all categories.
So we have broken windshield and flat tire and motorcycle involved,
vandalism and undamaged vehicles.
This will take some time.
So now, training is finished and let's do the system test image to see how it performs.
So you see here that's definitely vandalism and now let's take another one.
So, we are searching for broken tire.
So, maybe this one.
So, we take the link to the image and paste URL, hit enter.
You see here, it's a flat tire with 98% score. So, this is correct.
So as you can see here,
this is now a complete service deployed in the cloud,
but you still can train it so you can use it as an ordinary convolution,
deep learning image classifier.
But you don't have to care about scalability,
operations and also to parameterization of a new network you don't care about.
So, that's pretty cool.
So, let's see what else...