You have heard about orthogonalization.
How to set up your dev and test sets,
human level performance as a proxy for
Bayes's error and how to estimate
your avoidable bias and variance.
Let's pull it all together
into a set of guidelines for
how to improve the performance
of your learning algorithm.
So, I think getting a supervised learning
algorithm to work well means fundamentally
hoping or
assuming that you can do two things.
First is that you can fit
the training set pretty well and
you can think of this as roughly saying
that you can achieve low avoidable bias.
And the second thing you're assuming
can do well is that doing well in
the training set generalizes pretty
well to the dev set or the test set and
this is sort of saying that
variance is not too bad.
And in the spirit of thought organization,
what you see is that there's a second
set of knobs to fix the avoidable
bias issues such as training
[INAUDIBLE] or training longer.
And there's a separate set of things you
can use to address Damien's problems,
such as regularization or
getting more training data.
So to summarize of the process
seen in the last several videos,
if you want to improve the performance
of your machine on your system,
I would recommend looking at the
difference between your training error and
your proxy for base error and this gives
you a sense of the avoidable bias.
In other words, just how much better do
you think you should be trying to do on
your training set and then look at
the difference between your dev error and
your training error as an estimate.
So, it's how much of
a variance problem you have.
In other words,
how much harder you should be working to
make your performance generalize from
the training set to the desk set,
that it wasn't trained on explicitly?
So to whatever extent you want
to try to reduce avoidable bias,
I would try to apply tactics
like train a bigger model.
So, you can just do better on your
training sets or train longer.
Use a better optimization
algorithm such as.
Adds momentum or RMS prop,
or use a better algorithm like ADOM.
Or one of the thing you could try is to
just find a better new nether architecture
or better said, hyperparameters and this
could include everything from changing
the activation functions or changing
the number of layers or hidden do this.
Although you do that, it would be in
the direction of increasing the model size
to China other models or other models
architectures, such as the current neural
network and competitive neural networks
which we'll see in later courses.
Whether or
not a new neural network architecture will
fit your training set better is
sometimes hard to tell in events,
but sometimes you can get much better
results with a better architecture.
Next to the extent that you
find out variance is a problem.
Some of the many of the techniques you
could try, then includes the following.
You can try to get more data,
because getting more data to train on
could help you generalize better to
dev set data that you didn't see.
You could try regularization.
So this includes things like or dropout,
or data augmentation which she talks
about the in the previous course.
Or once again, you can also try
various neural network architecture,
hyperparameters search to
see if that can help you
find a new architecture that
is better suited for problem.
I think that this notion of bias or
avoidable bias and
there is one of those things that
easily learned, but tough to master and
we're able to systematically find
the concept from this week's videos.
You actually be much more efficient and
much more systematic and much more
strategic than a lot of machine learning
teams in terms of how to systematically
go by improving the performance
of their machine learning system.
So, that this week's whole work
will allow you to practice and
exercise more your understanding
of these concepts.
Best of luck with this homework and
I look forward to also seeing
you in next week's videos.
Variances are further