Welcome back.
In the last session, we have
discussed the anatomy of a LSTM node.
And today, we are going to look,
How the number of parameters is computed.
So let's have a look.
Here we have defined,
The LSTM layers with ten nodes.
So let's execute.
Okay, and then we can see here in the last
column, here the number of parameters.
And we see that for the first LSTM layer,
we have 480 parameters and for
the second LSTM layer,
we have even more, 840.
So let's see if we increase the number
of nodes to 20, what is going on.
So now we have even more.
So the first LSTM layer
has 1,760 parameters,
the second LSTM layer
has 3,280 parameters.
So where all those
figures are coming from?
So let's have a look.
What we have here is each
LSTM node has three gates.
So we have input gate, Sorry.
We have forget gate and
we have output gate.
We have also said that
the cell state is its memory.
Then we have also defined
the hidden state.
Hidden state is equivalent
to the cell output,
meaning LSTM hidden state size is the same
as number of nodes, or neurons,
which you have defined,
which we have to define and
this is the same as output size.
So lets have a look again.
So here, lets say again, ten.
Ten.
This LSTM layer has ten nodes.
So the output size is equal to ten.
It has one cell state,
three gates and ten output nodes.
What about input nodes?
Let us have a look and
compute for the first LSTM layer,
the number, Of parameters.
But first here is the formula,
how it's computed.
So we have the weights,
Of input size plus weights of output
size plus one bias variable.
Input plus output plus
output plus bias variable.
And this is all along
the output size vector
multiplied with three gates
plus cell state, so four.
So 4 multiplied LSTM output size,
multiplied with some input size plus
output size plus one bias variable.
So let us compute and
see it's actually pretty simple
if you have tried it by yourself.
So first of all,
we are taking the first LSTM layer.
This is the first LSTM layer,
First LSTM layer.
It has output size is equal to 10 or
this is the same as hidden state size.
How many inputs does it have?
Well, we have here, above it,
we have input layer.
And this input layer has dimension of one.
So the output of this
input layer is also one.
Therefore, we are computing it like this.
So three gates plus cell state is four,
multiplied
with output size which is
equal number of nodes,
is ten, multiplied with the sum and
then we have input size of
the first layer is one.
So it's receiving inputs from the first
input layer which has dimension one.
Output size again is ten and
one bias variable.
If we compute we are getting 480.
Let's see.
Yes.
We have 480.
Now let us have a look
at the second layer.
Second layer has again three
gates plus cell state four,
multiplied with output size is, again ten.
But input size is not one anymore,
but, ten.
Why?
Because it receiving the inputs
from the first LSTM layer
in the dimension of ten, it has ten nodes.
The output dimension is ten,
and the output dimension of
the first layer is the input
dimension of the second LSTM layer.
So we have the input size as ten,
the output size is again ten, and
one bias variable.
We are executing this and getting 840.
Let us see.
Yes, correct, 840.
So with this, enjoy our sessions,
and see you next time.
Bye, bye.