So let's actually see how this
example looks in real life.
Let's switch the model to healthy,
just to be sure.
So it starts to create data.
And in the notebook, you see data
arriving, one dot for each sample.
At the same time, they're using
the dashboard functionality of
the IBM Watson IOT platform,
in order to see what's going on.
So we see real time, time series plots and
displaying the data.
Later we expect anomaly score and
a lot to be populated.
Remember we've sent a no alert
message to the UI in the notebook.
Once the buffer is filled
with 3,000 elements,
data gets sent to the neural network for
training.
This is called account-based
tumbling window.
Other variants of stream processing
windows are time based, or
session based windows.
All of them can be tumbling or
sliding, but we will cover stream
computing in a separate class very soon.
So now the window was full and
was sent downstream to
the neural network for training.
It takes a little while, and
as Keras and TensorFlow are started, and
now are training stuff.
Here in training, we send the current
loss upstream to the queue.
So we should be able to
see it in the dashboard.
And as we can see, you started
with an anomaly score of 0.04, and
are slowly getting down.
This works as expected, since we're
looking at known and healthy data.
Our training is finished, and
usually the next windows of
data would have been processed.
But we've limited the tests data
generated to 3,000 events, so
we need to switch to program and reset.
By the higher amplitude we can make out
that the pattern of data has changed.
But the cool thing is that with LSTM
autoencoder based neural network,
we don't need to tell the neural network
how healthy and broken data looks like.
It finds out by itself,
a bit scary but totally awesome.
And again,
we need to wait until the window is full.
So training has just started, and
we immediately see that
an alert has been raised.
This is reflected in
the dashboard as well.
And in addition,
we see a clear spike in loss.
But we notice as well that
loss rapidly goes down,
since the neural network now gets used
to broken data, and sooner or later,
it considers broken data as healthy,
as well.
Therefore, the system has automatically
reset itself to the last known healthy
state by reloading
the pre-trend model from disk.
Those warnings are due to the fact that
communication with the message queue in
the Keras callback handler take some time,
but we can ignore those.
So this was an example of
an end-to-end scenario.
If you're happy with the solution,
we could easily export the model to
IBM Watson machine learning, because
running everything from a notebook for
a production scenario is not a good idea.
In a later lecture, we will also learn
how to make use of Apache Spark for
parallel neural network training and
scoring.
So stay tuned.