Hello, and
welcome to this part of the ghost.
My name is Max Pumperla and
I'm a Deep Learning Engineer at Skymind.
While my background is in pure
mathematics; I've been in data science and
in particular,
deep learning for many years.
I'm currently working on open-source
machine learning software for
the JBM such as the tensor library,
and for the 4J and
the deep learning framework,
deep learning 4J.
Also for which you will learn
more about later in this series.
In this part of the course, I will
introduce you to a popular high level deep
running library written
in Python called Keras.
I've been working with and contributing
to Keras over the last few years and
hope you would like it as much as I do.
In the next few videos you will see
how to quickly prototype deep learning
models using Keras elegant and
intuitive API, enjoy.