Okay, let's get started with
our introduction to Keras.
First off what is Keras,
and why would you use it?
Keras is a popular deep learning
framework written in Python.
It has been open sourced in 2015, and
it's excellent documentation
can be found on the keras.io.
In case you're interested,
the source code can be found on
GitHub under the following link.
Okay, why would you choose
Keras as your debugging tool?
There's quite a few aspects to it, and
one thing I want to mention is community.
Keras is a very popular library.
And as an active and
positive community that might help you
with any questions that you might have.
So for instance, you might direct your
questions towards the following Google
group or you join the following Slack
channel, and people could help you there.
Alright, another crucial aspect that
makes Keras a strong pick is its design.
Keras has an intuitive high-level
API that makes it very easy for
you to get started with first examples and
deep learning.
With this intuitive API,
you can quickly prototype new models and
have a very fast development and
prototyping cycle.
Also, Keras is built with very modular
building blocks and easy to extend.
So for instance,
if you want to build new custom layers,
that's quite easy to achieve with Keras.
Another thing that makes Keras
quite interesting is the ecosystem.
For instance, under the following
link you'll find many resources
on top of Keras,
that includes third party libraries,
as well as full-blown applications
built on top of Keras.
Also, Keras comes shipped with many end
to end examples that you can simply
check out and run.
On top of that,
in Keras you have many pre-built models
that have all ready been trained for you.
And there's quite a few data
sets available in Keras.
So that means,
you don't have to manually download many
of the standard data sets out there and
pre-process them.
But you can just load them
through the Keras API.
Another interesting aspect to
Keras is the concept of backends.
So one way to view Keras is, you can
see it as your deep learning front-end.
So essentially what Keras provides is
your high level entry point to
deep learning, but in the back,
what actually runs Keras is different
engines that do all the heavy lifting.
So there's a choice of
backends available for Keras.
First of all, there's Google Tensorflow,
which is also the default engine for
Keras.
And we will exclusively use
Tensorflow in this course.
Then there's theano, and
also Microsoft CNTK.
You can quite easily swap backends and
depending on your configuration,
Keras runs seamlessly on CPUs or GPUs.
So before we introduce the concepts
of Keras in more detail,
let's just have very first look,
a glimpse, at an example built with Keras.
First thing you do is,
you load the data set, in this case,
the mnist data set 400 digits,
directly through the Keras API.
Then, you define a model,
in this case, a sequential model.
After we have done so, you can just add
new layers to your model one by one.
After that, we compile our
model with a loss function and
an optimizer and
fit our model on training data.
On a high level,
that's all there is to it.
Every Keras example, more or
less looks like this.
All right, to install Keras,
we first have to install a backend, as we
said before we're using Tensorflow here.
So go ahead and install Tensorflow
with pip install Tensorflow.
Optionally, we also need to
install other dependencies.
[COUGH] For instance,
we need the library h5py for model.
So go ahead and
install it through pip installer h5py.
As last step, we need to install Keras
itself through pip installer keras.
All right,
that was the first introduction to Keras.
In the next video, we introduce
the sequential model API of Keras.