Hi. I'm John Cohn,
IBM fellow and Chief Scientist for the Watson IoT data center here in Munich,
and I want to welcome you to this wonderful start of
a class on Applied AI in Deep Learning,
done by my friend Romeo here.
You're going to love this class.
I'm taking it too,
and as somebody who's been on the sidelines of AI since the very beginning,
40 years ago, Marvin Minsky son was my roommate at MIT,
and talking to Marvin about neural nets,
I thought, "Yeah, like that's going to happen."
I went on to build devices like gaming processors that had GPUs.
Little did I know that at the other end of my 40 years that
I'd be using GPUs to help do real neural nets.
You're going to find that this is a great way to get into this.
As somebody who started on punch cards, now,
I'm using all the modern tools, TensorFlow,
Keras, Jupyter, and solving real problems.
Here, in this beautiful building in Munich,
we take in thousands of data points all the time on the building,
the air quality, the temperature,
the humidity, people flow,
control of the buildings, lights,
windows et cetera, and we are using Romeo's code,
the stuff that you're going to learn in this class,
to do deep learning and build
models that will help us determine what's normal and what's not normal.
We'll be able to do things like predicting
occupancy so we can pre-cool or pre-warm the building.
We're making it so that we can do all these experiments
using the infrastructure that you're going to learn in this excellent course.
So, thank you for checking in,
enjoy the course, and thank Romeo for me.
He's made it all very,
very easy for all.