Hello. My name is Dinerason.
I'm a data scientist at IBM Watson Health.
In this course, I have prepared for you
some very interesting sessions about sequence prediction
with LSTM and neural network and Kerras framework.
Let me introduce myself briefly.
My professional career I have started as medical doctor,
something which is completely different to data science.
Then I went to Germany and studied at
the University of Hamburg, Econometrics and Mathematics.
I was also lecturer for math for about five years at the University of Hamburg.
And since already five years,
I'm with IBM in Switzerland in Zurich.
And I'm very excited to be with you in this course.
And hope you will have great time,
excitement, and a lot of fun with our sessions.
So, see you in upcoming sessions.