Hi my name is Tom Hanlon.
I will be delivering the sections of this course that cover Deep Learning 4J.
Sometimes shortened to DL 4J.
And what DL 4J is,
is a tool kit for building neural networks using Java.
And although many data scientists work in Python,
the most widely used language in enterprise application space is Java.
So DL 4J aims to build a toolkit to focus on Java,
but also to help bridge that gap between Python and Java,
we provide a tool called Keras Model Import,
and this allows the loading of models that have been built in Keras using Python,
import them into DL 4J and deployed on the JVM,
in the Java environment.
In addition to the Keras Model Import,
some other features of DL 4J that I will be covering in this course will be executing DL
4J neural networks for either training or inference
where we just ask the neural net for its output on Sparke.
So in this courses I will be demonstrating Keras Model Import DL
4J execution on Sparke in
the IBM data science experience and also just
executing locally in Java on the data science experience.
If you wanted to learn more about DL 4J,
you can visit deeplearning4J.org for documentation,
examples and a quickstart guide that will help you set up
your java environment in intelliJ and IDE,
integrated developing environment to work with DL 4J directly.
Enjoy the course. Nice meeting you.