Hi, in this example I'm going to
demonstrate running Keras
models in DL4J in
the IBM Data Science Experience.
And it's going to be
a full end to end example.
So the contents of this
section are going to include
Python to Java all in the IBM DSX.
We're going to demonstrate
a classification example.
So I'm going to, use a simple
classification example where we got
four features and three classes,
and a relatively small data file.
But understand that the model we use
to execute that in DL4J is generic.
It will work with any
classification example
as long as the following
requirements are met.
The data has to be stored in
comma separated value files.
And it has to be a classification example.
That's it.
And then we get into DL4J we're
going to demonstrate validation.
But also note that the model
could be trained in DL4J.
So we'd have a choice of either
training the model in Keras,
in our notebook, or training the model
in DL4J in Java on Spark or Java.
So, All of the code that we're
going to demonstrate and all the work
that we're going to do here can be done on
the IBM Data Science Experience platform.
And the first step we're going to show
is on the IBM Data Science Experience,
we're going to build a Python Notebook.
And in that Python Notebook, we're
going to build and train a neural net.
So once we have our
Python Notebook in Keras,
a typical route would be to train
it in the data science experience.
And then once we've trained it
in the data science experience,
we could save the model.
And that's what we see
over here on the right.
Right, going from training
in DSX to the saved model.
But note that there's an alternative path.
And that is where we could
save just the configuration.
So perhaps we do a proof of concept
where we train it in Python but
we have more resources in Spark.
In that case we can take
the saved configuration and
as you'll see in the next
slide train that in DSX.
So from the Python notebook
we have these two paths.
Train in DSX, save the train model and
import that into DL4J
using our KerasModelImport functionality
or write the code in the Python Notebook.
Perhaps generate a proof-of-concept
over a small sample set of data.
And save just the configuration and
then import that into DL4J for training.
Once we have the model into DL4J, using
DL4J's KerasModelImport functionality,
note that we have an option of training
it on Spark, or training it locally,
just training it in Java,
by executing Java locally.
The path that I'm going to demonstrate
in this code is the Spark path,
executing it in Spark either for just
inference or validation or training it.
So let's walk through the code.
We're going to be doing
some classification.
And it's going to involve comma
separated values in a text file.
Here's an example you
may have seen before.
We're using the Iris DataSet,
4 features and 3 classes.
So even though our initial example here is
kind of like a Hello World, rather basic,
note that the KerasModelImport
functionality is generic, and
would work with any
classification example for
a large number of classes,
a large volume of data.
So our data file looks like this.
We have features, and then the last
column here is zero, one or two.
That is the class.
So we have three classes of flowers and
four features,
four measurements of those flowers.
So let's take a look at the Keras code.
So I'm going to import numpy,
import pandas, so some imports.
We're going to be using Keras so
we're going to use a feedforward network.
So we'll need Sequential API.
And we're going to do some
classification and some label encoding.
We set a random seed for
reproducible results.
That's right here.
So we get a consistent random seed.
And then we build a dataframe
from reading that iris.csv file.
Then we want to take the zero, ones, and
two, and
convert those to one-hot encoding.
So we're going to encode those values.
They could also have been text there, and
this code would work as well,
whether we have integers or text values.
It's taking a string, determining
the number of classes, and encoding that.
So what we have at the end of this step.
So we have our dummy_y and we have our x.
So you see we split our
dataset here into X and Y.
Once we split it into X and
Y, we manipulate Y.
So we get dummy encoding also
known as one hot encoding.
So at the end of that code,
we'll have the features file.
Notice that we now just
have the four features.
And this is the dataset X.
And the data set dummy_y
will have the labels.
And note that it's just one hot in coding,
all 0's except for one, so
this is class 0.
This would be class one, and
this would be class two.
So that just shows you how the data is
encoded for this example, here in Keras.
That's called one hot or
dummy encoding, for the labels.
Then we build a model.
So we add a dense layer,
we add our output layer, for
our three classes, specify the updater.
Straightforward neural
network configuration for
a simple feedforward neural network.
Then we train the model, and
then we save the model, okay?
So in this case we're doing what?
We're saving the trained model.
Note that the model could
be trained further or
we could have just saved
the configuration to train that in DL4J.
But in this case I am
saving the trained model.
So, this my_model.h5 file
will be the data file
that's loaded into DL4J
in the next section.
The DL4J code for this example
is available here at this URL.
And note that, that was just a single URL.
I broke it into two lines so
that it will display.
So what we do in the DL4J code, and
there's some boilerplate code and
some imports that I didn't include, but
the key features are,
we create a MultiLayerNetwork.
And the way we create that
MultiLayerNetwork is not manually in DL4J,
but by importing the KerasModel and
weights that we saved previously.
So when we execute this code, we'll be
generating this modelFileName based
upon a parameter that was passed
to this code to load our model.
So we're going to pass it our model.
And this bit of code will
take that model from Keras,
and create a MultiLayerNetwork.
Because we want to execute this in Spark
using a Data Science Experience's Spark
as a Service, we're going to need to set
up a ParameterAveragingTrainingMaster.
And so, what a training master does is,
for the workers, when they each finish
their forward pass and
they update their weights, at some point,
they need to share those weights so that
they're all working towards the same goal.
And in DL4J the tool that does
that is the training master.
And here, we're configuring
a ParameterAveragingTrainingMaster.
We need to create our Spark context.
And these two lines of
code here will do that.
So we have our
ParameterAveragingTrainingMaster,
our model, and our Spark context.
Now we need to tie them all together by
creating a SparkDl4jMultiLayer network.
And we pass this,
our Spark configuration, that you saw
configured in the previous slide.
And then we pass it our network and
the network you saw us
create here previously.
The network's generated by
reading that Keras file.
And then in addition to
the Spark configuration and
the network we need to
specify our training master.
Now we have all the pieces needed
to execute this code in Spark.
So when we execute this in Spark, we need
to pass our executable our data file.
And this training file gets
passed to each of the workers.
So what we do here is we're
going to read that file.
And then we're going to
create a list from that file.
And then from that list,
we're going to create an RDD.
That's a Resilient Distributive Dataset
that Spark uses for parallel processing.
So now we have everything needed
to do parallel processing on Spark
across this data file that we
shipped up to the Spark cluster.
And then we can train the network.
So the code will take
an optional train parameter.
So if we wanted to train the network
this code would take effect.
All right, so we're calling sparkNet.fit
on our dataset that we passed.
Or we can just run an evaluation, right?
If we're just using for inference,
if we're just taking the model and
only doing passing data in and
getting the model's prediction.
This code evaluates the network to
make sure we're getting consistent,
expected results.
And that's all we'll do in
the demonstration that I'll do next.
I will not train the network in Spark,
I'll train it in Keras.
I will import the train network,
pass it a data file, and
do an evaluation of the predictions
made by the neural net.
So that's the deal for Jcode.
That deal for Jcode has been bundled
up and placed into this jar.
So its been compiled and
placed into this dl4j-snapshot.jar
located at this location.
So in your notebook you'd
have to execute this command.
Note that we're using
!wget to escape Python and
execute this as a shell command.
This will download the file
locally in your notebook.
And once again, note that you could
do this with your own example.
Now, we built our model in our notebook.
So when we save the model,
the model will be saved locally.
So, this my_model.h5 file
will be available locally.
We're also going to make sure that we
have a copy of our iris.txt data file.
So, that's going to be available.
Note, in a previous slide
I called that iris.csv.
iris.txt is the correct name for
that file.
We're going to run spark-submit.
Submit it to the training master that's
made available to spark master, rather,
that's made available
in the DSX environment.
Specify that we want to run this class.
And that's the class of the code
walkthrough I just did,
the important Java pieces.
That's the KerasModelImport,
the Spark context and
the Spark DL4J multilayer along
with the training master.
That class is in this jar.
And then any options after the JAR
apply to the class itself.
So we're specifying the batch size,
we're specifying where the label is.
So in the case of our data file,
we had feature, feature, feature,
feature, four features,
and then we had a label.
So the label index in that case would
be the fifth field starting at zero.
That would be four.
So you specify the labels
are in the fourth column.
We say that we don't want to train it.
We just want to run inference,
we want to run evaluation basically.
Specify there's three classes.
So this iris.txt file has three classes,
three species of flowers.
We need to ship my_model.h5 and
specify my_model.h5
is the model to be loaded
in that KerasModelImport.
So right here, we need to make
sure that that file is shipped.
And then here we specify that this class
right there, should be loading that file.
And then specify the dataFileName.
And once again, that needs to be
available in the local directory
of the executor's or
the worker's, and that's it.
So in the next section I'm going to
actually demonstrate a code
walk-through where I execute this code.
Thank you.